You don't know me?
You really don't know?
I remember, but there's no need to remember it again, is there?
Is it okay for a girl to be running around stealing?
He called me a girl!
Didn't you see a tall guy?
I didn't see him.
What!
You disrespectful...
The guy who got hit, my sister beat him up.
Toe?
It's been a long time, I'm so happy to see you.
Du-han!
Ah, do you like coffee?
Do you like poetry?
Pardon?
I thought I had to do something, anything.
Anything.
So, to the gisaeng house...
I'm sorry.
Oh, right.
What kind of work did you say you do?
A small corner store.
I was in a partnership with a friend...
What do you sell?
We sell everything except for what we don't sell.
Really?
Even back then, I never thought you'd be a beggar.
Honestly, I get angry when I see beggars.
They could live by their own sweat, but begging is worse than stealing.
It's just like stealing from someone's conscience with an invisible hand.
Thank you so much for today.
You're the first person to ever say that to me, Yeon-ji.
The Daegu rice mill?
Yes.
It was really strange back then.
We...
You see, people in our line of work don't say 'thank you' much.
It's just "How much did you make?"
"Let's split it."
"Did you eat breakfast?"
"I ate well."
We only say things like that, never 'thank you'.
Can I come see you again?
I'm not a lady from a noble family.
And this place...
I'm not a young master from a noble house either.
Can I come see you again?
It's pathetic to see you throwing away money you earned through hard work at a gisaeng house.
To meet me...
If you don't have money to throw around, let's meet outside.
Can I come see you again?
Get home safely.
Let's meet again.
Did you close your eyes, afraid of losing me, like any other parting, to keep my reflection in your clear eyes forever? Oh fool, why didn't you know that when you left me, I hadn't even been able to show you all my love?
What did I tell you?
I told you this isn't a tiger's den, it's walking right into the tiger's mouth.
That Anchovy punk and Kim Du-han getting involved has made everything a dirty mess.
Just thinking about how much I got beaten by that girl makes my tongue feel like it's covered in thorns.
To these thugs, I must be the best medicine.
Even a saint has to be firm and teach those disobedient beggar punks a harsher lesson.
Let's grab a bowl of soup and go.
Welcome.
Miss, two bowls of soup please.
Yes.
I think my foot is broken.
It's not broken, just looks fractured.
It's definitely broken.
I can't walk.
But you walked all the way here.
I'm enduring it with willpower.
A guy like you couldn't even stand, but I'm different.
I told you not to glare at me with those damn dog eyes, it's bad luck.
Even if it's bad luck, I have to look at my nephew.
What?
What's wrong?
I'm going to show you what 'broken' really means, brother.
Are you crazy?
I'm not the crazy one. You're the one who drinks and fools around with girls all the time.
You haven't said a word yet, but we've already found out a lot about you.
Min-jae.
From the fact that you were a teacher at an elementary school to what books are on your bookshelf in your boarding room, we know it all.
You'll talk eventually, so it's better for you to confess now.
You won't have much time to act so proud.
After a few more wounds, you won't be able to keep your mouth shut.
Let me just say one thing.
In your language.
You bastard.
It's not a polite word, but you gave up on being a polite person a long time ago.
Damn it.
Why is only my foot freezing when I'm freezing all over?
I think he's dead.
If you're going to die, die quickly. Don't make people suffer.
Hey, bring me a handful of salt.
Why?
You have to sprinkle salt on a dead person's belly button so the ghost can't harm you.
Really?
Wow,
It's so white, isn't it?
Just a little bit.
It's a waste.
It's okay.
His belly button is so deep.
Wow, it all goes in, all of it.
Ah, you scared me.
Oh, you scared me to death.
Holding your breath like that.
You really scared me.
Stop making so much noise and get out.
Hey, Fly, aren't you going to work?
Yeah.
Who are you?
Getting shot and chased by Japanese patrolmen, you're either a robber or an independence fighter. Which one is it?
Are you mute?
Why aren't you answering?
Young master!
Have you come to your senses?
Don't you recognize me?
I'm Hongseong-daek's son, Bu-eongi.
No, I'm Man-seok.
Hey, Man-seok, what's wrong with you?
What do we do?
Do you recognize me now?
Young master, are you in a lot of pain?
Are you okay?
Stop calling me Young Master.
But if I don't call you Young Master, what should I call you, Young Master?
Just call me by my name.
How can I call you by your name?
You're not a dog or a pig.
I can't do that.
Then call me...
Boss!
Boss, we have a problem.
The patrolmen have followed us here.
Hey, open up.
Damn it, you bastard.
Hey,
We don't need to all take the fall for this guy.
What are you talking about?
Boss, you're not thinking of handing over our young master, are you?
If you hand our young master over to those Japanese dogs, he'll die.
If he dies, he dies. What's the big deal?
He's lived well so far, what more could he want?
Fate is in heaven's hands.
How can you just throw away a precious life like that?
Oh, you bastard.
We're all going to die.
There's no need to make a scene.
I hate causing trouble for others.
Hey, do you really have to do this?
Hey, Parrot, let's draw lots.
One for you, one for me, and wake up Raccoon.
Hey, is there any rotten bean paste left?
Kuroki-gun.
Yes.
This doesn't seem to be a beggar's shack.
No.
This is a dye factory. The shack is at the very end.
Lead the way.
Yes.
No, what's going on?
Move.
No, what's happening?
Beggars don't need to know.
Hey, you have to explain what's going on so we can help or not.
The suspect in the assassination attempt on Superintendent Endo in Jongno has appeared in front of Gukilguan.
Right, Gukilguan.
If it's Gukilguan, it's just a stone's throw from Supyodong Bridge.
Then wouldn't anyone, not just a beggar, flee under Supyogyo Bridge?
How dare they come all the way to Yeomcheon Bridge...
A patrolman of the Great Japanese Empire is giving an order to a Joseon beggar.
How dare you run your mouth and talk back?
Kuroki-gun.
Yes.
Let's go into the shack.
There's someone with a skin disease in there, so be careful.
We're so dirty it's fine for us, but they say it's easily spread to ordinary people.
You.
Lead the way.
What is that guy?
That's Gimbap.
All the trash in the Donggwanpyeong area is his responsibility.
Who asked you that?
Why is he like that?
I told you.
Skin disease.
Kuroki-gun.
Yes.
Hey!
Hey, get up!
Hey, friend.
Hey, even if you're a beggar, if you bathe properly once or twice a year like me, you won't end up in this state.
When did you ever bathe twice a year, you punk?
You bathed with me last Chuseok, when have you seen water since then?
You lying bastard.
Filthy bastards.
Damn it.
I'll wipe it for you.
The smell of rotten bean paste is no joke...
It's okay.
By the way, what's Gimbap?
Damn it, last year in the back alleys of Honmachi, there was a guy who would beat up drunk Gyeongseong University students and steal everything from their hats to their socks, pretending to be a mute beggar.
Did he get beaten up by the Boss and come down to Busan saying he was going back home?
He looks just like you, man.
Anyway, our Boss's mind works incredibly fast.
How did he think of smearing bean paste and using a mute beggar's name?
Right, Young Master?
I told you to stop calling me Young Master.
Just call me Gimbap.
Since I'm in the world of beggars, it's better to be called by a beggar's name.
Then if not Young Master, should I call you Mr. Gimbap...
What's with "Mr. Gimbap"?
It's just Gimbap.
Hey, Parrot.
Get Gimbap a begging gourd too.
Just giving him a begging gourd doesn't make him a beggar.
You know I don't turn away guests who come to my house.
But he didn't come to beg.
If we're not careful, the one who holds our family's lives in his hands...
Parrot.
Don't you have any spare begging gourds?
Boss, Boss.
The police are here again.
Move.
Hey, you, come out.
Hey, you punk, what are you looking at?
Come out.
Move, you bastard.
Boss, where are you going?
Boss.
Do you know how to smoke?
I heard you're a pretty smart beggar.
Who said that?
Am I some kind of owl?
Why would my head spin well?
You guys must go everywhere, digging through trash.
I go wherever I can set my feet.
I see.
I want to buy your eyes and feet.
There are 400,000 citizens in Gyeongseong.
In a wartime system, we can't let unruly elements run loose, but with our current manpower, we can't maintain perfect underground control.
We know everything, even when your back door falls off its hinges. So you want help from smelly beggars?
We're having trouble identifying the terrorists who have been assassinating government officials lately.
Even trash like you, when you think about it, are citizens of the empire who live under the grace of His Majesty the Emperor.
So?
When you're digging through trash and you find someone suspicious,
report it immediately.
If we catch the person the detective is looking for, what do we beggars get?
That guy is so important, his value can't be measured in money.
I'll give you whatever you want.
If you want money, I'll give you money. If you want land, I can give you land.
Remember this well.
He has a gunshot wound on his left arm and is on the tall side.
The woman who was caught with him is a real pain. No matter how much we beat her, she won't talk.
For now, I'm counting on you.
Abe-sa!
Seong-min says he'll talk.
He's going to talk about the accomplice?
Yes.
He said he'll write down everything he knows.
No matter how tough she pretends to be, she's still a woman.
She's a really difficult woman.
Man, that was tough.
When she said she'd confess, I gave her a brush, and she asked for a good pen that writes well.
So I gave her a fountain pen.
You foolish woman.
Let me go!
In the last moments of my life, I spit three curses on Japan.
The first is the Yasukuni Shrine.
The second is your national flag, the Hinomaru.
The third is the head of your dog leader, Emperor Hirohito.
Hey, Raccoon.
I'm taking food to the kids.
I don't know if their stomachs have gotten bigger, but they eat a lot.
Is it not enough?
No, that should be enough.
You kids, don't fight.
Hey, Crow.
Bring some food for Gimbap, too.
Hey, Young Master.
Get it yourself next time.
Am I your servant?
Why do I have to bring it to you every time?
Me too.
You eat too.
What are you looking at?
I told you to eat.
If you want more, just say so.
What's wrong?
Who is it?
The Boss went out today.
What are you talking about?
You can't fool a ghost.
Ever since we were rolling around in front of the tiny Daegu station, I've been able to tell if the Boss needs to piss or take a dump just by looking at his face.
He's like a police dog, man.
Gimbap?
That Gimbap guy.
If we bring him here, our family will be in danger too.
I'll take care of it.
I'm just saying this because I'm worried they'll sniff him out.
Once those dogs get a scent, they'll...
Hey.
I made the decision.
Alright.
Boss uncle, you know about the party tomorrow, right?
Huh?
What?
It's the day the city's four main gates open. They said they're holding a ritual and want us to have a good time.
In January, the night sky is adorned with brilliant stars. Holding a zither, the Jinju gisaeng Nongae throws herself into the Namgang River, embracing her enemy. In March, a pair of swallows flies in on the third day. Holding a zither, another month passes. On a busy road, lunch is skipped. Enjoying a drink, Guan Yu of the Three Kingdoms appears.
You go first.
I'll watch a little longer and come.
The six generals, Han Jeong-jin, applaud...
Hey, friends, let's have some fun, friends...
Is everything alright?
Yes, yes.
Can I see the ledger?
Here you go.
Oh, I was wondering where that fishy smell was coming from. A quail chick is sitting next to an old eagle.
Hey, I haven't seen you around before. Come here.
Just stay seated.
Which bitch started selling her face in Jongno without reporting to Double-Blade?
Do you not know who I am?
It smells rotten in here.
Open the door.
What?
Are only the Japanese customers, and you look down on Joseon people?
I've never discriminated between Japanese and Korean customers, and I plan to keep it that way. I'm talking about people, not mice.
Not a mouse.
How dare you talk like that in front of me?
Look!
You better watch out for mouse holes.
Don't let your stocks fall again here.
Are you in front of me?
Hey!
You punk!
You must be very angry.
You said you get angry when you see beggars because guys like me are bad people who live by stealing other people's conscience.
I'm sorry.
For lying.
Business?
I'm in the beggar business.
Actually, I'm really...
You don't have to say you won't meet me again.
I know that much.
Even if I'm a beggar, I won't come looking for you in a pathetic way.
I'm sorry.
For making you angry.
Yes.
I'm angry right now.
I've always hated beggars.
When I see beggars who beg even though they can earn a living on their own, I get so angry I want to hit them.
And what makes me even angrier is myself.
Even though I know what kind of person you are, I can't bring myself to think that I shouldn't meet you.
I...
Because of money, I gave up the thing I wanted most in the world.
But what I need is money.
Not a man with a lot of money.
What did you say?
Can you please say what you just said one more time?
No.
I don't remember what I said.
Can I visit you again?
Pardon?
What kind of book are you looking for?
Uh.
Not a book.
I came to buy a poem.
Huh?
A poem?
Yes.
That...
That strange person's poem?
How much is one of those?
University! University!
University!
Let's go!
Alright!
Where?
Over there!
Let's go!
Get in, quick!
Rock paper scissors!
Hurry!
Scissors!
Rock paper scissors!
I won!
How's the tea?
I'm much better.
Thank you.
Thanks to you.
What's this?
Huh?
What's that note?
No, this is...
It's a poem.
A Hungarian poem...
A poem?
Yes.
A poem.
Ah... a poem.
Then you must know Yi Sang.
Pardon?
Yi Sang.
He... he died in Tokyo a while ago, right?
I know Yi Sang.
But...
How do you know Yi Sang?
From lying.
Hey, you mute.
Even if I look like this, I've even been to the tea house that Yi Sang used to run and had coffee.
I'm sorry.
That's not what I meant...
Hey.
See?
This is Yi Sang's poetry collection.
Yes, but...
Are all educated people like that?
Hey, what are you looking down on me for living under a bridge?
No, that's not it...
I was just surprised that the Boss was reading a poetry book...
I'm not reading it, I'm giving it to someone.
Really?
If you're giving a poetry book as a gift, it must be for a woman.
Yes, I'm giving it as a gift.
I received this from a woman, too.
Hey, try reading this.
This might be a bit difficult...
"Crow's Eye View."
Thirteen children are running down the road, and the road is a dead end.
The first child says he's scared.
The second child also says he's scared.
The third child also says he's scared.
The fourth child also says he's scared.
The fifth child also says he's scared.
The sixth child also says he's scared.
Are you reading it correctly?
Yes.
Should I keep reading?
That's enough.
Anyway, try reading your note.
Liberty, my love.
For you, I would give my life.
But, my love.
For liberty, I would give even you.
Liberty?
Yes, liberty.
I know about that.
It means doing whatever you want, right?
But to give your life for that?
It means freedom from oppression and bondage.
Something we've lost for over 30 years.
A country where you can live according to your own thoughts without interference from others...
What about here?
Pardon?
Here, at Yeomcheon Bridge.
No one asks what kind of dog bone you were in the past.
They don't care, and they don't ask.
It's your freedom to come and go as you please.
You don't take from others, and you don't steal.
There's nothing to take, and nothing to hide.
If you have something, you share it. If you have your own, you can have it.
Well, that's true, but...
You're on the run right now, aren't you?
No one comes looking for you here.
No one even stops by.
Even though it's a dark shack where the sun doesn't shine, you can live freely as you please.
You can rest here as long as you want, as comfortably as you want, and no one will interfere.
Where else can you find this kind of freedom right now?
Boss!
There's trouble.
I think you need to go to the store right away.
Hurry, hurry.
Hey, move aside, ladies!
Hey, what's this?
Who did this...
Double-Blade.
Why would Double-Blade do this?
Other stores are already paying 30 won, but they were making a fuss because we were only paying 20 won...
Did Double-Blade come himself?
Double-Blade just stood outside for a moment, and his underlings came in and smashed everything!
Does Du-han know about this?
I don't know.
Bring the ledger!
20 bottles of beauty water, 15 jeon each, 3 won.
What are you going to do, open it?
If you want to get compensation, you have to know how much was damaged.
Are you crazy?
You're going to get money from Double-Blade?
How many tubs of cream are left?
S-six.
Hey, Hyeongdo.
How are you going to get money from Double-Blade?
I'm going to go to Double-Blade right now with Du-han.
Double-Blade knows you're Du-han's friend.
The total is 120 won.
Hey, sir, really.
If something like this happened, you should have told me first.
Why did this have to happen while I was in Mapo?
Are you going to keep pretending you don't know?
What are you talking about?
You don't know what you are right now?
Is your fist a rock, or is your head a rock?
What?
Since I received the grand prize!
What misunderstanding!
Have I been putting up with you all this time?
Don't talk recklessly!
What do you mean, recklessly?
I told you not to be reckless!
Sit down!
Double-Blade messed up your shop to show off to you, Du-han.
Double-Blade isn't a fool.
He knows a tiger can't stay under a wolf forever.
What are you talking about?
The merchants at the night market want you to take over the patrol, not the increasingly brutal Double-Blade.
You know that too.
I can't do that!
He's my senior, how can I...
Hey, you idiot.
You think Double-Blade sees you that naively?
Stop with the nonsense!
My boss would never do that!
Hey, Du-han!
It's foolish to swing your fist when you shouldn't.
But it's even more foolish not to use your fist when you absolutely have to.
I'll take care of your business myself.
What is it?
What's going on now?
I'm seeing you for the first time, but I've heard your name so much it's made my ears bleed.
Ever since I was a kid, I thought Double-Blade was the greatest man after Admiral Yi Sun-sin.
I've respected you for a long time.
Weren't you in Daegu back then?
No, that...
Even if I was in Daegu, your name is famous, sir.
Is there anywhere in the country I haven't been?
I have nothing to say but to ask for your guidance, sir.
If a person like you just gives the word, I'll do anything...
Hey, you punk!
Why are you being so subservient?
No, it's just...
It's not subservience.
I was just trying to get your permission to manage the beggars who crawl around Jongno.
Hey, hey, you can do whatever you want with that.
Those beggar punks are none of my business.
Hey, I'll give you salt for that.
Give me that book that the kids are scared of.
No, are you going to go like this?
Women value what they can see.
Of course, a smart woman wouldn't think that's everything.
Still, unless you're blind, it's better to be dressed cleanly.
Hey, Crow!
Crow!
Why, why, Boss?
What?
What's wrong?
Oh, what's wrong?
Hey, did you return the overcoat you stole last time?
Of course.
Really?
Yeah.
Where is it?
It's gone.
Hey, tell me the truth. I won't get mad.
It's true.
Really?
Yeah, you know I can't lie.
Hey, just wear it once today and give it back.
I told you I returned it!
Who's going to wear it?
Me.
The Boss is going to wear it?
Yeah.
Really?
Hey, I only need to wear it once today.
Hey, Fly!
Bring the overcoat!
They really don't pay their debts.
These bastards.
Two, three, four, five.
There's no answer.
Oh, President Im.
Is business good?
You're here?
Hey, is this the thing the king gave to his favorite lover?
King Sejong.
How much is one of these?
50 jeon.
Hey, let me have it on credit.
I'll pay you back tenfold later.
You're going to pay me back 5 won?
In ten years.
You're a real thick-skinned bastard.
Then lend me 150,000 won while you're at it.
You eat it.
You can't just eat it.
You have to peel it first.
A long time ago, King Sejong gave this to his favorite woman as a gift.
Today, that bitter and delicious soup...
I'll buy it for you.
Coffee?
Yes, coffee.
That looks good on you.
It's an old coat.
So what if it's old?
Sometimes old is better.
I used to like everything new, too.
Books, notebooks, and bags.
I even preferred hanging out with new friends.
I found anything old to be a bit boring and uninteresting.
But now it's different.
As time goes by, everything gets a little old, doesn't it?
Right?
Yes.
Now I prefer things that are a little old rather than new.
There's no sense of loss when something new fades.
Old things are much more comfortable, right?
They feel more comfortable.
Let's go.
Let's go eat something more delicious than coffee today.
What's this?
This...
Yi Sang's "Crow's Eye View"...
is in here.
Are you giving this to me?
A gift?
Yes.
A gift.
Thank you.
Oh, you like poetry too, Chunsam.
No.
Not really.
Uh... "Crow's Eye View" is supposed to be a picture drawn by a crow...
That's right.
A bird's-eye view seen by a crow from the sky.
It's unique, isn't it?
But why a crow of all things? It's bad luck.
Do you like crows, Yeon-ji?
No.
The one I like is the poem "Mirror"...
You know "Mirror," right?
Yes.
I know.
"Mirror."
I still don't get it, no matter how many times I read it.
But this one seems like it will give me an even bigger headache.
Right?
You think so too, Yeon-ji?
All of Mr. Yi Sang's poems are like that.
Me too.
I'd rather...
a nightingale or a cuckoo would be better.
Pardon?
A cuckoo?
Yes.
A cuckoo.
Cuckoos are much cuter, their songs are nice...
You know the cuckoo, right?
Cuckoo.
Yes.
Cuckoo...
You know, right?
Right?
Cuckoo.
Cuckoo...
But...
It's bad luck.
Crows are.
They're dirty, filthy, and noisy...
But the crow in "Crow's Eye View"...
My mom...
In my hometown, people hate crows.
Yes.
A magpie...
might be different, you know?
Hello, sir.
What?
I'm Lee Jung-jae.
Lee Jung-jae?
Do you remember me?
I bought the champion bull at the wrestling match when I was young.
I treated you to dinner at Hanilgwan.
Right, right, right.
Jung-jae.
It's been a long time.
How have you been?
Yes.
I opened a small store in the market.
So?
Is there a problem?
Kim Du-han's underlings have been showing up in front of my store lately and causing trouble.
Du-han?
Seeing them cause trouble in a place even you don't frequent, sir, it's clear Kim Du-han has other intentions.
If you just give me permission, sir, I'll meet Kim Du-han myself and teach him a lesson.
You don't have to.
Just run your business well.
I'll teach that Du-han kid a lesson myself.
No, sir.
He's an underling you raised yourself, sir. It must be difficult for you in many ways. I'll do it myself...
I told you, just mind your own business and run your store.
Hey, call Du-han.
I raised a snot-nosed kid who sold fish-shaped bread in a theater, and now he thinks he can take me on?
No, sir.
What do you mean, no, you bastard?
Do you want to die by my hand today?
I'd be honored, sir.
Please kill me.
What are you doing?
You took me in when I was just a street urchin selling things.
If it wasn't for you, sir, I'd still be selling chrysanthemum bread.
But...
I, Kim Du-han, may not be a very smart man, but I never forget a debt.
No matter how the world changes, even if the sky and the earth were to grind together, you will always be my boss.
So what, you bastard!
I want to be a loyal subordinate who speaks the truth to such a boss.
Your reputation has been tarnished, sir.
You've changed too much, sir!
You've really grown up, haven't you?
Who cooked the meat today?
Was it Anseong-daek?
You didn't cut the meat to my liking, so didn't I have to pull out a knife to cut it myself?
Cut this piece again.
What's this?
I didn't call for a sixty-year-old grandmother.
The winter drought must be severe.
It seems not only the old trees have withered and died, but also the handsome men.
You can't find a real man anywhere.
What?
Do you know that there isn't a single person in this town who doesn't know that you'd dance in your underwear in front of rich foreigners to make money?
If you're going to know, know it properly.
That time, it wasn't my underwear, it was a slip.
A slip or whatever, what do I care what women wear under their clothes?
Hey!
When I see men who just talk big like you, chirping like sparrows, I can't help but laugh.
You son of a bitch!
Sir.
I'm sorry.
I never thought the day would come when I'd have to take off my jacket in front of you, sir.
Thank you.
Since you're showing me respect, I should do the same.
I hope I won't have to use this knife.
If you ever let me get hit on purpose, that knife will be stuck in your heart.
Let go!
Anchovy!
Let's have a good, hard fight until our bones are crushed.
It's been 30 years in Jongno, 30 years with these fists. Just as my
sister was crazy about the Boss, are you crazy about that woman?
I can only think of that woman.
Did that Kim Chunsam person give you that?
Ah!
Please!
They will never put a prisoner in a hospital gown on the gallows.
Min-jae is in that hospital?
Fine.
I'm going in again.