Mister, is this for real?
Is this really Daegu?
Aren't you going to get lost?
You want a beating, you brat!
Ah!
It's Daegu!
Get your sweet potatoes!
Give me some sweet potatoes.
Yes.
Ma'am, cow dung!
Cow dung!
Ma'am, here's your handbag.
Oh, thank you.
Hey, my ring!
Oh!
Oh, thank you!
Hey, lady! Do you know where you are?
How dare you cause a scene here?
Why did you lie?
This is Daegu.
Give me back my apple.
What's with this kid?
Think getting that "hick" sign off your forehead was free?
Give me back my apple!
Why is this yours?
I put my teeth marks on it, so it's mine.
Give it back.
Get lost!
Give me back the apple.
No!
Get lost!
Boss!
What's this?
Parrot, did your little chick show up?
You gonna look?
It'll get jinxed if you guys look...
No!
Let's see!
Let me see!
No!
Be quiet.
Let me see!
I said let me see!
Hey!
Bring that over here.
Hurry up and bring it!
Or I'll wring your damn neck!
It's the Boss!
Boss!
What is it?
Is there no one with you?
Loma!
Lay out your bowls.
What are you saying?
Put it all out.
Rat Droppings!
That's it? You're useless.
Midal!
Next up, Loach!
One scoop of rice, a handful of barley, three pieces of rice cake.
There's a dried pollack head here, too.
The pollack head passes. Pass.
Scraps!
Yes.
Boss, please give this kid a piece of cloth.
What good is bringing back just one?
No, sir.
I'll bring back a cleaner one.
The other one was too dirty, so I threw it out.
Leave it here, kid.
Parrot.
Yes?
One bowl of soup, two pieces of barley, half a stick of taffy.
And a one-jeon jujube.
You're a beggar sent from heaven.
Come here.
Wow, Parrot got praised. He must be happy.
What about your selfish hoarding, Yellow?
I saw everything at the station earlier.
No, that's not it.
The birds were chasing me, so I dropped it while I was running away.
Pour it.
Yes.
If Yellow really shows up, what happens to Parrot?
He won't be able to beg for another month.
The Boss will yank out both his fangs.
Take off your pants too, punk.
Come here.
Parrot, look me straight in the eyes.
Straight!
If you lie, you die.
Toe, bring me a skewer.
Hey, bring a skewer.
Lie down properly!
Now, let's take a look at your bare ass.
It's true!
I was running because I thought the guy
with the birds would catch me, and I dropped it!
Is that true?
Yes.
Maybe his mouth is just shaped for lying?
Beggars are brothers.
Brothers beg together and share everything equally.
Got it?
Yes.
Take care.
What the...?
What's going on?
What's happening?
Shake 'em all awake!
Where have you been sleeping?
Hey, shake 'em all.
This punk...
Shake 'em all awake!
Alright, that's enough.
Stop it and sleep!
I'd have no regrets if I could just have some hot soup.
I don't even need it to be hot. If I could just have one sip of soup...
I'm getting hungrier because I can't sleep.
It's not that you're hungry because you can't
sleep. You can't sleep because you're hungry.
Why am I always hungry, even after I've eaten?
You idiot. Beggars have a hunger ghost attached
to them. You can't not be hungry even if you want to.
Stop talking nonsense and go to sleep.
Should we play the rice cake naming game?
Shut up.
Are you crazy?
My back and stomach are already stuck together,
and you want to brag about rice cakes? What the hell?
Injeolmi. Is injeolmi a rice cake?
Yes, it's a rice cake.
Steamed rice cake.
Right.
Glutinous rice cake.
White rice cake, the one we eat on New Year's Day.
Hotteok.
Hotteok isn't a rice cake, it's bread.
They sell hotteok at bakeries, not rice cake shops.
So it's bread.
Hotteok is a type of dog rice cake.
It doesn't matter where they sell it.
Dog.
It's Toe's turn to sleep.
Hurry up and sleep.
Lights out.
Hotteok is a rice cake, too.
Hotteok is not a rice cake.
You lose.
Then...
Is bindaetteok a rice cake?
Hey, where did Injeolmi go?
Maybe he went to take a leak.
That kid looks dazed, but he's got no sense.
What's this kid doing?
It's the Boss!
Did you guys do this?
You damn punks!
Your stomachs must be empty.
Eat.
Let him eat.
If any of you lay a finger on him, I won't let it slide!
Hey, bring him here.
What's wrong?
Let go!
Can't you shut your mouth?
Let go, you bastard!
Shut up!
You're dead if you get caught.
I'm thirsty. Go get some water from those guys.
If you don't want to get beaten to death by the Boss...
tell him you weren't hit.
Got it?
Did they hit you again?
You damn punks!
No, that's not it.
I fell down.
Is that true?
Yes.
Hey, Anchovy, give him something to eat.
What are you most afraid of in the world?
A strong fist? A rich guy? That's all bullshit.
The scariest thing in the world is hunger.
If a drunk dog and a hungry dog fight, who do you think wins?
The hungry dog wins.
You know why?
When your stomach is empty, you see nothing and
fear nothing. As scary as hunger is, having a full stomach
feels amazing and makes life worth living. That's
why beggars are the most blessed people in the world.
Because you know how scary hunger is and how good a full stomach feels.
Isn't your heart more at peace than even Buddha's?
Take this.
From now on, this begging gourd
will be a weapon more fearsome
than any gun or knife. Go out
there and wield this weapon well.
The beggar who came last year...
Let's rest, rest, and go in. The
beggar who came last year is
back again without dying. Let's
rest, rest, and go in. First up!
Hey, have a good day.
You guys have a Chuseok house today, right?
Got it.
Let's watch together.
Hey, Yeong-se.
Train him well.
I will.
You should know you're incredibly lucky.
Having a beggar as skilled as me in all of Joseon as your teacher.
Watch carefully.
Punk, that's not it.
Those aren't the eyes of a beggar.
You think you can just look with those wide-open eyes?
It's a sin for a beggar not to look like a beggar.
To be a beggar, you have to walk
like a beggar, and breathe like a beggar.
Got it?
To look truly pathetic like a real beggar, look at me, look at me.
Let your eyes droop, and your mouth...
Forget it.
I'll just do it my way.
Hey, hey! If you do as I say, even if you don't have parents...
You're my student, punk!
My yellow cloth!
What are you going to do with this?
When I was little, a fortune teller told me.
If I don't carry something yellow on me, an
evil spirit will attach itself to me and I'll die.
Thanks.
I'll make you the most skilled beggar there is.
When it comes to begging, scrap metal,
and other skills, no one can match me.
I don't need any of that.
Then what can I do for you?
Just say the word, I'll grant it.
I only want one thing.
Please look here.
This young man here has come to find his mother.
His name is Kim Chunsam, and his mother's name is Park-sil.
Open your eyes and look carefully.
Has anyone lost a son as handsome as a Formica doll?
Chunsam, Sansam, whatever. No one here has lost a son.
Just make some noise and get going.
That lady, even if I don't give her a
burnt rice crust, she's always yelling.
What's that punk saying?
If we just go around the laundromats and
markets, we can meet all the women in the world.
Even if your mom sleeps in and doesn't leave the house, don't worry.
Aren't women all talk, anyway?
They know more about who lost a son in
whose house than they know about their own.
This is money, you punk.
Ma'am, I brought the fermented urine water.
Oh, you're here.
I was just about to wash the holiday clothes.
Perfect timing.
Here you go.
Thank you.
Off you go.
Two.
One.
Three.
Four.
Get up.
What are you talking about?
Yes, thank you.
Come here.
This is where they keep the props.
You pack up quickly, too.
This is the loan shark's house.
Since he's a damn loan shark, you
have to piss on it every time you pass by.
It's even better if you take a dump on it.
Rest, rest, and here we go.
Chunsam, who came last year,
has come to find his mother.
He came all the way to Daegu.
We're screwed again today.
It's only been three days.
Do you know how big Daegu is?
It'll take more than a month to search everywhere.
Oh, Chunsam.
Oh...
Oh, my baby, where have you been?
Oh, you're nothing but skin and bones. Your spirit is completely gone.
Oh, you look worse for wear than a wild beast.
Oh, my poor baby.
Oh, this mother hasn't been able to sleep a single
night with her legs stretched out since I lost you.
Every night, I'd curl up like a
frog, soaking my blanket with tears.
Oh, now that I've found you, there's
nothing more to say, Chunsam.
Oh, my poor baby.
Mom... are you really my mom?
Of course, of course.
Let's go home, quickly.
Anchovy, I've repaid my debt now.
I'll say you ran away, so you have to live well with your mom.
Oh, don't you worry.
Anchovy, you're so lucky.
You have a mom now...
Take care, you punk!
Oh, my frog-like son.
Every night, as soon as the sun went down, I'd lie down.
Hoping to meet you even in my dreams.
But now I've finally met you in person.
Hey, what's this?
You're not a beggar anymore.
Give that to me.
The house is a mess, right?
Oh,
There's no man around to fix things.
So the outside is a mess.
Mother...
My sister...
Oh dear, why are you asking about your sister?
She fell off a cliff while being chased by hunters...
Oh my goodness.
What are we to do?
Mother, I'm sorry.
No, it's not your fault.
Forget about it.
What's the use of a girl?
I have a strong son like you here.
But still, my sister...
Stop talking about your sister.
It'll only break your heart.
What good will it do?
Hey, you must be hungry.
Go inside.
I'll prepare a meal for you.
Can't you speak?
Yes.
Hey, when was the last time you ate a proper meal?
I don't know.
The day before yesterday?
Then what have you been eating?
Rice water, cabbage scraps, radish tops...
Oh my, oh my.
They say if someone who hasn't eaten well suddenly
eats a lot, their stomach gets shocked and they can die.
You're my precious son.
Something bad could happen.
Make sure to chew each bite a hundred times.
If your stomach settles, this mother will give you all her rice.
Yes.
Living alone, this mother has suffered terribly just to survive.
You must take good care of your mother and be a good son.
Yes.
But, Mother, your new husband, my father...
Oh my.
Don't even mention him.
He caught a disease and died within two years.
Oh, this mother has no luck with husbands.
A tiger startled by a hedgehog...
will even jump at a chestnut burr.
Now, I just get a fright even seeing a mountain's shadow.
Oh my, you've eaten so much.
Maybe a sleep demon has possessed you.
Oh my, oh my, oh my.
But, Mother...
Hmm?
If you're done eating, go over there and sleep.
What if my sister...
Didn't I tell you to stop talking about your sister?
She's dead.
Are you going to stop or not?
The living must go on.
Oh, my back.
Oh, oh.
My neuralgia is acting up again.
Black frog.
Sis!
Yes.
Get up and eat something.
The sun is high in the sky. If you keep sleeping like that,
you and I will end up starving.
No, I'm strong.
Oh, hey, that hurts.
Oh, with your mother's back aching from
neuralgia, you should have at least started a fire.
I'm afraid the floor will get cold.
Hey, hey, put me down.
You know you're like a pumpkin vine.
This mother worked her butt off to bring this here.
Even the king can't get this for free.
Chunsam, you go clean the pigsty.
If you leave it like that, the pig will die in its own filth.
Hurry.
My, my, our Chunsam is strong as an ox.
That's enough.
Now, go to the mountain and get some firewood.
Your mother's neuralgia makes it hard
to move, and I couldn't sleep all night.
Yes.
The more I think about it, the crazier it seems.
That person is different from others. Do
you think I'd sell it for a penny to just anyone?
Still, it seems too expensive.
Oh, come on.
I'll throw in this hairpin for you.
Alright, see you next time.
Yeah.
Mother, I brought back a lot of branches and pine needles.
Oh, you've worked hard.
Tired, aren't you?
No.
Whatever Mother asks me to do is not tiring at all.
Oh, why do you always say the exact same things your father used to?
You're so alike.
Oh, I guess the spirits didn't mess up.
Mother, your back hurts, so go lie down.
I'll make dinner.
Oh, look at me, so forgetful.
You must be so hungry.
Hey, Chunsam, go cook the pig slop.
Yes.
Do you have a place to stay?
Oh.
What brings you here?
Didn't I tell you to wait there?
That's what I was told.
What can I do? I was getting anxious.
Shut up, punk.
Please, hurry.
Does that beggar kid even work hard?
Well...
I'm living like a dog under a big tree now.
A notoriously stingy woman like you? What's going on?
Why would you bring in a kid you're not
even related to and cause such a scene?
No, if I just wait a bit, he'll grow into a strong
young man. What could be better than this?
No need for wages, and if he gets sick
from eating scraps, I can just kick him out.
Come here.
Oh, oh.
Oh, he's so demanding.
Come here.
Oh, oh.
That tickles.
Chunsam, there's rice and side dishes in the
kitchen, so help yourself. I'll be back by sunset.
Oh, you scared me.
Oh, you nearly gave me a heart attack.
Mother.
What?
There was something I wanted to ask you when I found you.
Hey, stopping a busy person like this...
We can talk about that later...
When is my birthday?
Your birthday?
Well, let me see...
It was well after the first month.
Oh, it must have been around spring.
Uh, maybe early March?
Oh, I'll tell you the exact date after I get back from my errand.
My grandmother said it was in the fall.
When the persimmons were ripe.
Oh, that's right, that's right.
Right, your sister was born in the spring.
You were born in the fall, that's right.
What day?
Well, let me see...
Hey, what are you doing, stopping a person with a long way to go?
I'll tell you in the evening.
No,
Girls don't have belly buttons.
That's why they wear skirts.
If they don't have belly buttons, why wear skirts?
You idiot, since they don't
have a belly button for air to pass
through, they wear skirts so it
can pass through from below.
So girls have belly buttons?
No.
Yes.
If you don't know anything, just stay quiet, you punks.
Girls have belly buttons.
Have you seen one?
Later, a baby comes out of there, pop!
That's how it works.
Got it, you punk?
That one's thick.
How much is it?
How much?
It's a watermelon.
It's a watermelon, you punks.
Let go, you bastards.
You punks.
Even if you found a job, you should have
asked for my permission before leaving.
Why did you come back?
What happened?
She was a fake mother.
You're lucky to be alive.
Are you okay?
Yes.
Toe.
Divide what's left of Anchovy's share among the others.
Yes.
Pollack, Loach, go get the rice.
Are there fake mothers?
I wish I had a mother, even a fake one.
I have one.
A really pretty one. I have a real mother.
Stop lying.
How could a kid like you have a mother?
It's true.
Do you want to go see my mom right now?
Don't bluff.
Is your mom prettier than a courtesan?
Of course. A courtesan isn't even
as pretty as the sole of my mom's foot.
Is she prettier than the schoolgirls in sailor uniforms?
Prettier than the schoolgirls?
Not even as pretty as the sole of my mom's foot.
Hey, hey, let's go!
Run, run!
Have you ever heard of a drifting water weed?
Oh, please don't use difficult words.
We don't understand difficult things.
It's difficult, very difficult.
Ah, this is annoying.
Sigh.
Oh, how annoying.
Today Daejeon, tomorrow Gyeongseong.
The loneliness of this drifting water weed, wandering here and there.
Which one is your mom?
That old lady?
Are your eyes blind?
Just you wait and see.
Oh, there she is. My mom.
I told you, she's a drifting water weed.
Let go.
Why don't you just settle down?
Mother.
Ugh, let go of me.
Is my own mother hitting me, you punk?
Then maybe I should just die.
Get away from me, you punk.
You bastard.
My meal ticket, this...
Do you know how expensive this is, punk?
You damn bastard.
Get lost, you bastard.
Hey, let's go.
Hey, what's this?
What's this?
Get away.
You can't get away.
Help me.
I can't get away.
Oh, you little punk.
Hey.
Ah, this kid.
Are you hurt?
Are you okay?
Look here.
What did I tell you?
I told you not to come out.
My son said he missed his mother, so I brought him.
I missed you too.
When the full moon comes, I'll ask
my boss for a day off and come see you.
The day of the great full moon is our Sunnam's birthday, right?
Right?
I'll bring our Sunnam's favorite rice cakes and come find you.
You share them with your friends.
Okay?
No.
You don't have to come.
I know you're busy making money, Mother.
As long as my Sunnam isn't sick, I have nothing to worry about.
Save your money quickly.
We have to buy our house.
Then Mother and Sunnam can live together, right?
Now, you should go.
I have to get back to work.
Here, buy something to eat with your friends.
No.
I don't want it.
You save your money, and I'll save
mine, so we can buy our house quickly.
Stop talking and take it.
Sunnam.
Oh,
Are you hurt?
Are you okay?
The hat, the hat.
You damn punk.
Your head is so hard.
A few hits won't hurt you.
I won't let that guy get away.
I'll teach him a lesson.
Let's catch him when he's walking at
night, cover him with a mat, and beat him up.
Put dog poop in his hat, just one step away...
That's a good one.
You idiot, what's that?
You should smear poop all over his face.
Don't do anything.
If my mother gets beaten up again
because of that, it'll be a big problem.
You bastard.
What did you beggars eat today?
You're in for it today.
What do we do? The Boss is bleeding from his head.
You're dead, you bastard.
This bastard.
You're going to bleed today.
What's going on?
Let go, you bastard.
Let go.
You bastard.
What do we do? The Boss is being taken away.
Hey, what happens if the Boss gets taken away?
Toe.
Punishment meal.
Boss, just like you said, I've brought
it with a lot of sand and sawdust.
This is a true punishment meal.
From now on, no complaints. Gulp it down in one go.
Do I have to wring your damn neck for you to eat it?
Swallow it in one gulp so the sound
can be heard all the way to the village.
Aren't you going to eat properly?
Why is Toe becoming the new boss?
He's the strongest, after all.
Next, Rat Droppings.
Hey, Mackerel Pike.
You keep eating.
You idiot.
When was the last time you managed to beg for a grain of rice?
Even a mouse is better at begging than you.
Hey, Frog.
Go get the punishment meal.
Put a lot of sand in it and give it to him.
And you call that begging?
You useless fool.
You're worse at begging than a mouse.
Is there a bigger idiot among idiots?
Get beaten to a pulp.
Damn it.
Hey, you useless bastards, what are you doing?
Why aren't you out there begging?
Do you want to starve to death?
Why are there so many coins?
Don't touch it.
It's all mine.
I'd rather die with you guys.
Show me.
Hey, hey.
What is it?
Let me see this.
No.
Not this.
This is my mother's.
Absolutely not.
We are brothers.
We beg together and share everything equally.
Watch carefully what happens to a guy who tries to survive on his own.
Rat Droppings.
Rat Droppings, are you okay?
Parrot, say something.
I think Rat Droppings is sleeping.
He's not sleeping.
Hurry up and talk to him.
Rat Droppings, Parrot.
Stay right there.
Hey, did a guardian come?
No.
I'm not a real beggar.
I'm just pretending to be a beggar until I
save enough money to buy our house back.
My mother and I were kicked out of our
house because of a debt my father left.
Since I'm a big kid, no one would take my mother in.
So I came to the beggar's den on my own.
After ten nights, I go to see my mother once.
No matter how much I miss her, I have to endure it.
My mother is really pretty, right?
Do any of you have a mother as pretty as mine?
You don't, right?
Sunnam!
What's this?
Why are you like this?
Sunnam!
Rat Droppings is dead.
You killed him!
Are you challenging me now?
Yes.
With fists?
Or with guts?
Either one.
Fine.
Tomorrow morning, we play the train game.
Anchovy is truly insane.
Toe is so tough, he'll lie
there until the train's about to
hit his forehead. How can
you possibly win against that?
What if he gets killed?
He'll end up like Rat Droppings.
You think Toe will let it slide?
Hey!
Hurry up!
Why are you suddenly so jumpy?
It's the train!
The train is coming!
Hey, you punk!
Get up!
Why...
What are girls to you, punk?
Thanks.
Mother!
M-Z!
Boss!
Where are you going again?
M-Z