Precise [STT] by knoe.ai
Subtitles_Translations_Timing
Hey!
Get up!
Hey, you!
Anchovy!
Don't just leave him.
Why?
We have to take Anchovy's body with us.
Anchovy!
He's perfectly fine over here.
Hey, Toe, you lost.
Chunsam won.
That's right!
From now on, Anchovy is the Boss!
Hey!
You have to leave the records behind!
You think you can hog all the feasts and funerals for yourself?
Hand it over when I'm asking nicely!
Says who? When I think of Rat Droppings, I could kill you.
Parrot, you won't get away with this either!
You damn beggar bastards!
You think you can just live comfortably with your legs spread?
When?
You don't know when you'll become a pile of ash!
Toe!
You better live the rest of your life straight, you punk!
If you ever step foot near our turf again, I'll snap your legs!
We've come a long way!
Look at these punks!
We haven't even finished the barley powder!
You can't find it, so get lost!
Oh my!
Even if he only eats rice, he can't eat meat and will just be a bag of bones!
Look at these punks!
His legs are going to get twisted!
You damn punks!
Stretch your hand out further.
No, this won't do. Let's just go. No, he looks like my brother. Boss, what are you doing?
Just go. Don't touch them. Bury them properly.
Let's just go. Why are the women next to you, punk? Should I mess with you because I'm scared?
Brother!
What for?
Big brother!
Big brother, come here, quick!
Come here, quick!
Yeon-ji, let's go!
Let's go!
This...
Did you take this from those gangsters?
Are you okay?
Are you hurt?
Thanks.
Yeon-ji, after you graduate, are you going to Tokyo to study dance?
Yeah. If you come and they make me study something other than dance, there's only one thing I can do. What do you think that is?
Jumping into the Hyeonhaetan Sea? Oh, who's going to believe that lie?
My family doesn't have the money to send me for more studies. What am I going to do now?
Here, eat this and go. Weren't you on your way to the bathroom?
Leave the bowl and go.
Idiot!
Some lady has been waiting for a while. She said she was your mom.
Chunsam,
Do you recognize your mom, Chunsam?
Ma'am, what's your last name?
Park. The Miryang Park clan. I came to Daegu from Jangseong seven years ago. Do you know what my old house looked like? People called it the tile-roofed house. A stream flowed behind the house, and there were three persimmon trees in the yard. My... my child... who?
Your... your older uncle is living there. Mother!
Chunsam!
And your sister?
What happened to your sister?
I sent people to your grandmother's house in Jangseong several times. Mother...
Your sister?
I'm sorry. What is there to be sorry about?
If the Boss leaves, I'll be the new Boss. You're lucky, Boss. Your mother looks like a rich lady. Boss, take me with you. If you take me, I'll eat less. This kid has no sense. Why would the Boss take a troublesome guy like you?
Take care. Whether you can fill the kids' stomachs is up to the Boss. Parrot, you'll do well. Because you're the most skilled beggar in Daegu. I'm not coming back here ever again. I'm never coming back.
Oh, what's that smell? This stinky kid. Hold on. I'm going to adopt this kid. Samsun, you want to see your bathwater?
It's so clear, you could eat it as soup when you're hungry. Just watch your mouth. New lady, take your new son. I understand. My real son has finally returned. It's not shameful that you lived as a beggar. What could a child without parents do?
But from now on, you must not live like you used to. Understand?
Change your clothes, and let's go greet your father first.
I'm back from school. That's your brother. Nice to meet you. I wanted a little brother too. Ah, yes.
Nice to meet you. Oh, you must have suffered a lot.
You should bow to your father first.
A deep bow. That's right, Chunsam. When you bow to an adult, your forehead should touch the floor.
Chunsam, that's enough, that's enough. Why be so strict from the very beginning?
Manners are something you learn over time. Sit down, sit down.
How many meals have you skipped?
You must have starved a lot when you were a beggar, right?
How many days did you starve?
Well, about two or three days?
How did you feel after starving for two or three days?
You saw nothing, right?
Here's the thing. If you starve for two days, you'll eat rotten food. After a week, you'll even eat rats. And if it's more than six days, then...
Then what happens if you starve for six days?
Vampires... Vampires that live by drinking human blood. That's how they're born. What's that?
You're ignorant. You'll learn it all in school. A long time ago in Europe, they punished criminals by locking them in caves and starving them to death. Eventually, they started eating each other, and a few became vampires.
You almost became a bloodsucking vampire. What a shame. Hello.
My name is Kim. Hello.
My name is...
Shall we try it one by one?
Hello.
My name is Song. Hello, Mr. Park.
My name is Mr. Park. Hello, Teacher Jeong.
My name is Teacher Jeong. Then, Mr. Kim, Mr. Kim, Teacher Kim Chun.
Mr. Kim, what's your name?
What's your name? Teacher Kim Chun.
Mr. Kim, how old are you?
Age... How old are you? Ten... ten... four... ten years old.
Uh, come in.
Is there a loud person in the house?
Does a loud person often come to your house?
Wow, are you curious?
Come here.
There's a little person inside who sings. Liar. Even if he lies, his ears can't. Do you want to listen?
The voice is just like a person's. I was right, wasn't I?
I've only seen it once, but they say if you shake this box a lot, people even smaller than dwarves pop out. Do you want to try?
Hurry up and shake it.
Harder, harder.
Oh my, this... Oh my, what do I do? I'll try to fix it somehow. Fix it?
Do you think there's a technician in all of Joseon who can fix this?
My uncle bought this for me in Tokyo, a German product. Do I know about music? What do I know?
I've lived my life just for the pleasure of listening to this one thing. Oh, it's a disaster.
If you wanted to listen to it, you should have just asked. Your father treasures this so much. How could you touch it so carelessly?
That's enough. Go to your room.
Mother, don't scold him too much. It's his first time seeing a phonograph, he must have been so curious.
Hey, Parrot!
It's you guys. What brings you all the way here?
Where is a beggar not welcome? There are no invitations, no rules for begging, no need for requests. You guys are using fancy words?
In our territory, there are two schools and four temples. A dog at a school for three years learns to recite poetry. We've picked up a few phrases while begging around the schools. How is it, not bad?
Yeah, but the smell from the school's outhouse is really something. That's right, it's worse than a scholar's poop.
By the way, what's that smell?
Is that rice cakes?
What's going on?
The Ulsan lady!
Scrape everything out of the cauldron, even the burnt rice. What's going on?
Why are you pulling?
Why are you so stingy?
Jun-seo!
Are you okay?
It's okay.
Such a small kid, but so fearless.
Thank you. That's enough. How was it?
With this, we can take on those Japanese guys, right?
Hmm, hmm, hmm. Well, you passed the test. Well done. Hey, Jin-seong!
Aren't you going to listen to me?
Hey, I've got a fight with a Japanese guy at the cathedral. If you win, I'll give you half of my winnings. Don't want it. If you win this time, you'll be my guard. And I'll introduce you to some famous gangsters in the city. Didn't I tell you to wash up? Where's the soap?
Just because I took in a dirty beggar, washed him, and clothed him, do you think you can do whatever you want?
Huh?
Look at this guy. How dare he glare at me like that? Hey, you're just a parasite living off someone else's family, aren't you? Aren't you going to listen to me?
If you don't listen to me, from now on, you and your mother won't get a single drop of soup in this house. You got that? Hey, you!
Do you want to die?
Why are you insulting my mom, you bastard! You gangster!
What are you doing?
Do you want to die?
You gangsters, stop it!
Hey, aren't you going to get lost, you punk!
Aren't you going to get lost? Is the Boss at home right now?
He should be. He's back from school. But if Toe finds out we snitched on him to the Boss, he won't let it slide, right?
He definitely won't let it slide. Then there's no choice. Whether we tell on him or do him a favor, we'll get ripped off either way. This is it. Oh my.
I don't see the Boss, only a delicious rice ball. Hey, you punk!
What are you trying to steal?
You beggar kids! Hey, you punk!
You frog, you're alone?
What do we do?
You punk, let's go! You damn punk!
What's wrong?
You're scared now, you punk! No, I just need to meet the Boss. These beggar kids are loitering around, you punk!
Stop hitting him!
We came to see the Boss, why are you hitting us?
That's enough. Aren't you going to get lost, you punk?
Dong-min! Dong-min, how did this happen?
Who did this?
You're the Boss, Chunsam, right?
Chunsam must be different because he's a beggar king. His mother must be happy. You just show off your strength to your older brother. Yes, well done.
Where are you coming from?
I asked where you're coming from.
Did you do something so bad you can't even tell your mother?
Did you bring that child here?
No, right?
Chunsam, you promised me you wouldn't meet those kids again. This has nothing to do with you, right?
Yes, that child must have just wandered in to steal something. Right?
He came because of me. I told him it was okay to meet me. He...
Please let him go. I'll let the child go. Come in here.
Hurry up and go. Frog is waiting. Boss, I'm going to see Toe tomorrow. I'm dead.
Chunsam, I told you so many times not to associate with those beggar children. Abandoning a child once already drove a nail into this mother's heart. Not again. Never again. Is anyone out there?
Lock this child in the storeroom. Don't let him go anywhere until I say so.
Chunsam, are you asleep?
Your mother has sinned greatly.
I'm sorry for my many sins. How could I hit you? How could I hit the child I finally found?
Because of a mere two bags of rice, I left my two children behind to remarry. But not a single day passed when I didn't think of you and your sister.
Your poor sister.
Your poor sister became food for beasts in the forest.
I'm the one who deserves to die. If only I hadn't abandoned you two.
Yes, maybe it would be more comfortable to just live with you.
For you, what wouldn't I do, even if it meant selling my labor?
What's the use of sleeping under silk blankets if your heart is not at peace?
Yes, before it's too late, let's try to live together, just the two of us.
I've boiled some tangerine and ginger tea for you.
Drink it to warm yourself up and go to sleep.
Mother, please forgive me.
What happened?
What happened to you guys?
He might die.
Let me see.
Where's Parrot?
I asked where Parrot is!
Parrot!
Where's Parrot, you punk!
Anchovy, you!
My eye!
Anchovy!
Anchovy, my eye!
Are you okay?
You're not hurt badly?
Look, your teeth.
Don't worry.
I've never seen anyone die from eating with one hand.
That's a relief.
Boss!
Parrot, listen up.
From now on, you have to take good care of the kids.
What about you?
I'm going to Gyeongseong.
Gyeongseong?
What about your mother?
I ran away from home.
Even if I have to beg, I'm going to live in the big city. Got it?
Yeah, good thinking.
I'll go with you.
No, you stay here.
Take care, Parrot.
Boss!
Where are you going again?
Where are you going?
Let's go together.
Parrot, you can't go.
I'm originally from Gyeongseong.
You don't know the area well.
Gyeongseong is so complicated and scary.
Don't worry and just take care of the kids.
Don't follow me.
I said don't follow me.
I said don't follow me!
Boss, when are you coming back?
You guys... are you trying to die, you punks!
You don't even know the Meiji Bridge is melting.
The chrysanthemum bread from Bukmidang has long since gone cold.
It's the talk of the town, where one of two could drown in tears and no one would know.
Director Lee Gyu-won's "The Tree"...
When will he come if he takes the ferry?
No, when will he come if he goes?
Don't follow me.
Hey, Yeong-deok.
What happened to getting the free tickets?
I'll definitely get them next time.
You're supposed to be good at getting hit, and you can't even get that?
Cheon-seong, we don't need to get involved.
Hey, you're hitting a kid, you bastard.
Run, run, run.
Hey, Su-dam, run!
Hey, hurry!
Ah, I almost died.
What's... what's this?
It's from the warehouse.
Ah, from the warehouse.
How did you get it?
Even ordinary people can't get a look at this.
You're making such a fuss over something that looks like a pumpkin seed?
If it weren't for our Boss today, you would have been killed by those guys.
Don't you talk.
Among my friends, there's a guy who can take down not just three, but four guys at once.
Gyeongseong folks really brag a lot.
Now you know, right?
It's true.
He's Kim Du-han, a guy who sells fish-shaped bread in our country. He even won a fight against a gangster when he was a kid.
Come here, come here.
This, this, this punk.
Come here, come here, come here.
No, we didn't do it.
Some other beggar kids did it.
It wasn't us.
Where are these other beggar kids?
Hey, you beggar punks.
You're always stealing, you bastards.
Just leave him alone.
He didn't do anything wrong.
Shut up, you punk.
You stay out of it and get lost.
Won't you let go of my arm, punk?
Scram.
This punk.
Now they've added seasoning to the noodle dough.
They added seasoning.
Hey, you punk.
Stop right there!
Stop there!
Hey, you beggar punks.
Hey, thanks.
You're the first person I've met who's faster than me.
What's your name?
Deong-chi.
My real name is Kim Du-han.
The beggars in Gyeongseong are quick-witted.
And they brag a lot.
The kids from Gyeongseong only talk big.
They're scared and have no grit.
That's right.
I used to live at Supyogyo, but the Boss is too old.
The Gwanggyo area is tough because of the troublemakers. I think Yeomcheon Bridge will be the easiest.
Yeah.
The Yeomcheon Bridge Boss seems like he's all talk and no guts.
I was aiming for that place from the start.
You have to crush the spirit of the Gyeongseong kids right from the start.
If you show them you're stronger than their Boss, they'll all come over to your side right away.
Good luck.
If you need my fists, come to Umigwan anytime.
Take care.
Hey guys.
They say eating this will make you really strong.
The beekeeper's father at Tapgol Park said so.
He really said that.
I'm already strong without eating this stuff.
Hey.
It's good to be stronger.
Then no one can hit you.
Right.
There's poison in this stinger.
The strength comes from the stinger.
The beekeeper's father said so.
He said Xiang Yu became a great general after eating a hundred of these bees.
Hurry up and eat.
Boss.
No.
Hurry up and eat.
Boss.
Hey.
Who's the Boss here?
Who are you?
Anchovy from Daegu.
From now on, I'm going to live here.
What?
We're already living here. How can you live here too?
Are you crazy?
Really.
You guys just have to become my underlings.
You want to be my underlings?
No.
You said it backwards.
Are you opposing me right now?
Here.
Chunsam, Du-han, what are you doing?
Hurry up.
What's this?
Hurry up and eat.
Hey.
It's just like you, hyungdo.
You've come to feed us.
Du-han.
Your fists protected us.
Did you hear about Chunsam beating up the forest kids yesterday?
Yeah.
Really?
Teacher.
Did you enjoy the movie?
Excuse me.
Excuse me, sir.
Sir.
Yeon-ju.
Excuse me.
Sir.
Move.
Help me.
Get him.
You bastard.
Move.
I'm sorry.
Should I just kill you?
You damn thief.
I didn't mean to steal it, why are you doing this?
Do you know how much this is worth?
This punk.
Really, sir, it came out with the expensive stuff.
A ten-won item. I'm sorry.
I only have a thousand won, this bastard.
I really didn't mean to.
My hand just... without me knowing.
I'm really sorry.
I'm sorry.
You bastard.
Why are you stealing other people's things?
It's because of my hand.
You bastard.
You keep stealing other people's things because of your hand.
You had no intention, but your hand stole it on its own.
Right?
It's because of this hand.
You bastard.
It was the hand's fault.
The hand did it on its own.
You bastard.
Keep an eye on your hand.
Trusting the five won you earn with your hand,
our kids in the shack are starving.
Because of you, ten beggars might starve to death.
Got it?
Hey, Hyeongdo.
Don't cry, man.
Don't you ever lay a hand on my kids again without my permission.
Got it?
Fine.
But don't ever ask me to make him a thief again.
I'll send you a well-behaved one.
Forget it.
You might as well entrust a fish to a cat.
Hey, my kids don't steal.
You know that one is a bit special.
Please.
Just take one less mouth to feed.
Send him over.
Are you okay?
I'm okay, Boss.
Is being okay enough, man?
I hit him to bring him to his senses.
Wipe it.
Hey, this is called beauty water.
I'll give you the address, and you just have your guys deliver it.
Hey, I should have my kids wash up before sending them.
It's cosmetics, after all. If smelly beggars deliver it, it'll ruin the image.
You have to do it after business hours.
You're really reciting poetry.
Hey, you punk.
Do you even know what that is, wiping it like a rag?
Isn't it something to eat?
It is something to eat, man.
They're 50 jeon each. What if you burst them?
You think just anyone can eat tangerines?
This is so precious that King Sejong himself gave it as a prize at his first banquet.
It's very precious.
Don't even touch it.
Wipe the window.
Is it Anchovy from Yeomcheon Bridge?
You've expanded your territory all the way to Seodaemun Yeongcheon, has your stomach gotten that big?
If the number of mouths has increased, shouldn't the taxes increase automatically?
Don't you know that taxes increase with the number of heads?
We'll try to increase it gradually.
Right now, we're in a tough spot just trying to get the cobwebs out of our kids' throats.
Do you know why you got hit?
I just don't like the look in this punk's eyes.
When you look at me with those eyes, smiling like that, my insides twist like a fried dough stick, you bastard.
Are you smiling?
Don't smile.
You need to learn to lower your eyes in front of an adult.
What?
Don't worry about other people's eyes. Just keep an eye on your own hands.
Get lost.
Why are you getting involved with beggars?
You want to fight?
Do you want to end up on the cutting board today?
No taffy seller would refuse a customer who wants to buy.
Let's go.
Cheon-seong
Precise [STT] by knoe.ai
Subtitles_Translations_Timing