Anchovy, have you been well?
You'll know who I am just by hearing my voice.
In just a few days, a day more important than the one I lost my energy will come...
That day is the day I lost my eye.
Once a year...
I chew on a pollack head...
The closer that day gets, the more I think of you...
Didn't I tell you?
Maybe he's happy because he knocked down Anchovy.
[PTT] Subtitles by knoe.ai
Precise Translation & Timing
Stop, stop, stop!
Are you okay?
Take it easy, you wild boar.
You be careful on your way in.
Thanks.
It's a robber!
Don't you know me?
I'm a beggar, you punk.
What kind of robber robs a beggar?
Huh?
It's Fly!
Fly!
Your tiny face has gotten even smaller.
Are you okay?
Sit here, sit here.
Do your teeth hurt?
He put a hole in my tooth.
Hey, you must have gotten beaten up really bad.
How did your face get like this?
Hey, are you okay?
Of course I'm okay, man.
Get some water.
Hey, Barefoot, get some water.
Hey, you idiot, what happened to you?
Why, why, why, why?
Where do you think you're going!
Where have you been, showing up now!
Bewitched by that vixen, you didn't even know your shack family was being beaten to a pulp, and now you're ignoring the guy who has your leg in a cast!
My teeth are sensitive.
They're vicious bastards.
They said they'll take two people every day until the Boss is caught.
No, getting beaten is better.
That guy with the glasses, the teacher or whatever...
My teeth are sensitive.
He said he's coming back tomorrow morning.
Boss, you need to lay low for a while.
If the Boss gets caught, all his teeth will be pulled out and he'll be killed.
Everyone, gather around.
I think I need to leave the shack for a while.
It won't be for long.
While I'm gone, Parrot.
Got it.
And absolutely no stealing or begging.
Fly, huh?
I'll...
Okay.
And Raccoon.
Don't skip cleaning the market.
I'll keep an eye on it.
Hama.
It's been a while since you've collected from Hanilgwan, right?
I've been busy going back and forth between the gisaeng house and the hospital, but I'll take care of it.
And...
I'm sorry to you all.
It's already hard enough to get by, and I couldn't even take good care of you...
From tomorrow morning, there will be no more trouble in the shack.
Boss!
He's crazy.
Completely crazy.
Look at him running away to hide in that gisaeng's skirt even after being beaten like that.
The Boss is going to the police station on his own two feet.
Are you going to turn yourself in?
Are you going to the police station now?
Yeah.
It's going to be tough.
Think about it again.
There's nothing to think about.
The sooner I go, the better.
I met that woman at the gisaeng house.
She's waiting for the Boss.
Left Foot!
Huh?
You go to the Nambak shack and spread the word.
Yeah, got it.
Hama, you take Supyogyo.
Fly, you?
You're still sick, right?
No, hyung.
I'm fine.
I'll run to Cheonggyecheon.
Okay.
Raccoon, you?
Yeah.
Yeongcheon.
Seodaemun.
I'll take Mapo.
Spread the word well.
Yes.
Tell them that Kim Chunsam, the Boss of Yeomcheon Bridge, got arrested for punching a Japanese guy.
Got it?
Let me offer you a drink.
Drink up.
Are you from Yeomcheon Bridge?
The Boss is waiting for you.
Where?
He said to call the Cloud Moon.
The Cloud Moon?
I understand.
Thank you.
Yeong-jae.
I've missed you.
A lot.
Are you hurt?
Are you in a lot of pain?
I got this in a hurry, so it's not much, but it should be enough to hide for a while.
Use this to go outside the Namdong Gate and send a person for me.
I'll come find you as soon as possible.
I'm sorry.
This all happened because of me, I'm so...
It's too dark in here.
Come here.
I want to see your face, eyes, nose, and mouth clearly, Yeon-ji.
We can meet again in a fortnight.
We.
I can't go outside the Namdong Gate.
Pardon?
Why?
If I go, my family will get hurt.
I can't run away by myself.
It's because you don't know that person.
He might even do something to you, Chunsam.
At worst, I'll just have to rot in prison for a few months.
A few months in prison?
I won't allow it.
Ordinary people can do whatever they want, but a Boss is different.
What's so different?
It's your life, you can do whatever you want.
There's a new scholar in our shack, and he told me about freedom and love.
But until now, I've lived my life doing whatever I wanted, freely...
But... so that's changed.
Do you regret it?
No.
It's just that I feel like the way I live has changed a bit...
How?
Until now, I've only lived under the Yeomcheon Bridge, where the sun never shines...
But now, the sun shines day and night.
A very bright sunlight.
I want to live my life seeing you whenever I miss you, and holding your hand whenever I want to.
Take care.
Can I see you again?
Hey, Kalchi!
Long time no see.
Did you hear the news?
Yeah.
Where's a guy like Chunsam-hyung?
Those bastards.
Did something happen?
Let's go.
Pardon?
Hey, Do-ah, hurry up and come out, man!
Hey, what's going on?
Hey, did you see that seat?
Manager Abe!
Look at that!
Let's get this party started! The beggar who came last year is back again! The dumba is spinning well. The penny I got this morning, I'll offer it to my master.
The spoiled rice I got this evening, I'll offer it to my master's dog.
The pumba is dancing well, hey, the pumba is dancing well. Our master who is like Confucius, our master who is like an apricot blossom, our beautiful master. Master, master, forsythia. Master, master, forsythia.
What's this?
Let go!
Hey!
Disperse them quickly!
Military police!
It's the military police!
Get the military police, quickly!
What happened to the military police?
Don't get caught!
Cheon-ssaem,
What about Cheon-ssaem?
He's at the police station.
Let's go inside and talk.
A guy like you...
I can't believe a beggar would dare to assault an imperial officer of the Great Japanese Empire.
And yet, that's not enough, so he's inciting the beggars!
Cheon-ssaem!
Do you like poetry?
Yes.
Oh, so you like poetry too, Cheon-ssaem.
Do you like crows, Yeon-ji?
No.
I think a nightingale or a cuckoo would be better.
Pardon?
A cuckoo?
Because of money, I gave up what I wanted most in the world.
But what I need is money, not a man with a lot of money.
Can you say what you just said one more time?
No.
I don't remember what I said.
Can I come see you again?
Yeah.
I hope you get well soon.
As I've always said, there's only one thing I want from you.
They say a Joseon gisaeng is a flower that understands words, but it seems some flowers have no ears.
Judging by how you don't understand my words.
I don't listen to words that are not worth listening to.
There are two kinds of women in the world.
A woman who becomes more charming the more you see her, and a woman who becomes less appealing the more you see her.
I think you're the second kind.
Really?
But the more I dislike a woman, the more I feel compelled to possess her.
That guy is going to prison.
You seem to have a special relationship with him.
I've picked out a special place for him.
The front lines of the South Sea Islands.
The war situation is bad, so it will be difficult for him to come back alive.
Oh no.
Just sleep.
When you've been beaten, sleeping is the best medicine.
If the Boss dies, I'll die too.
You can drink right now?
Of course, I'm so upset.
Is that the face of an upset person?
I'm going crazy because of that Chunsam guy.
That's why I'm drinking, so I don't go crazy.
This is no time to be drinking.
Chunsam must be a ghost by now from all the beatings.
Then will you take the beating for him?
A friend is someone who dies with you and gets beaten with you.
Instead of getting beaten together, it's a hundred times better to bring him some rice cakes.
Meat is even better.
Don't worry about that Chunsam guy.
He'll never die.
He's the guy who survived even after being caught by a tiger when he was a kid.
Oh, it's cold.
If you're going to treat someone like a person, you should treat them like a person.
This freezing cold air is seeping into my bones. How can a person survive without freezing to death?
Shouldn't you at least give us a heater or a hot water bottle?
Chunsam, shut up!
You have to give me a reason to shut up.
If you give me a disease, you should also give me the cure.
You beat the kid until he was completely broken.
You don't even care about him like a dog.
You just threw him a lump of rice and that's it.
What kind of law is this?
Oh, you bad people.
Please stop.
Don't get dragged in and get beaten up.
Are you saying I have a big liver?
Even if it's not a Japanese world, a person should be able to say what they want to say.
Even if I have to go, I have to say what I have to say.
This will be your first and last visit.
If you're taken to the South Seas in April, you won't be able to come back.
Does that person know too?
What should I do?
This is all because of me...
I'm fine.
I don't have to worry about starving to death, and as long as I have a strong will, I can endure it.
You don't need to worry about me.
I'll just eat the prison food and endure it for a few months, and then I'll be out.
Don't come here again, Yeon-ji.
I don't like you coming to a place like this.
Why?
I'm here to see you, Chunsam. Who cares what anyone says?
Still, this place is...
I don't care.
I'll be out soon. Let's meet then.
Can I see you again?
When I get out, we can go eat hotteok together and go to the Swallow Cafe...
Coffee...
Yes, we can drink coffee.
You don't have to read to me, Crow.
Actually, I don't understand a single word of this.
It's the same for everyone.
They just pretend to know.
Until I met you, Yeon-ji, I never once thought I needed to learn how to read. But since meeting you, I've become frustrated.
When I get out, I'll send my kids to school.
Even if they're beggars, they should live like human beings.
I know you're a better person than anyone else, even if you have nothing and are uneducated.
Especially to me.
You look even prettier when you smile, Yeon-ji.
I...
When I think of you, I can do anything.
Pardon?
First, don't get hurt.
Go inside.
You go first.
I'll watch you go in.
This is my house, and you're my guest, so you go first.
Please don't get hurt.
If you're well, Yeon-ji, then I'm well too.
Come in.
Please let that person go.
It's too late.
The roster has already been sent, so even the Governor-General can't do anything about it.
You can do it, Director.
I'm grateful that you value my abilities more than the Governor-General, but you've come too late.
In a fortnight, you'll receive that man's ashes.
Please.
I'll do anything you want.
Anything.
Just please release that person.
And I'll see you tomorrow night at Huian-gak.
Thank you for soothing my lonely heart all this time.
Life is so futile, but thanks to you, I've lived a less futile life than others.
Why are you being so dramatic, you idiot?
From now on, you'll never meet a man as handsome as me again, not even in your dreams.
Where are you going?
I'm going to die now.
Is that a letter you write when you're about to die?
What's a letter you write when you're about to die?
A suicide note.
Are you going to die after writing a suicide note?
That's not it.
I received a notice that I'm being drafted to Sakhalin.
Do beggars get those too?
I'm on a different level from other beggars who don't even know their last name.
I have parents, a name, and everything is on the national registry. If I don't go, my father will go instead.
Didn't he say he doesn't even treat you like a son?
Still, he's my father.
Yeong-seon.
What are you doing, calling me by my real name?
We're parting ways with passionate love, what kind of mood would it be if I called you Crow?
You try calling me that too.
Hama.
Not Hama, call me Mr. Hong-pal.
Mr. Hong-pal, take care.
Yeah.
Take care of your one and only life.
Hey, Hama!
You clueless fool.
Read this.
I went to Gyeongseong Bukcheong Restaurant, and instead of giving me the fodder I asked for, they just gave me this useless piece of paper.
So you didn't bring anything?
So the kids have to starve again?
You got the same thing?
Who's Park Man-su?
There's no such person here.
That's my real name.
You have a name?
Yes, my grandfather gave it to me when I was young...
You arrogant fool.
No, but Hama and Myeongtae, that's one thing, but we don't have a clan. How did we get a draft notice?
You must have a clan.
Your address and name are all on it.
We don't have names.
He must be confused because it's in Chinese characters.
Gimbap, you read it.
Kim Aeng-mu...
Yeo-gu-ri?
Raccoon?
Aeng-mu?
Parrot?
Is that my name?
What about me?
Lee Mam-bal.
Why am I Mam-bal?
I'm Barefoot.
Hey, you ignorant fool.
It's because it's written in Chinese characters.
Ah, wait a minute.
Don't I have a name?
Girls are not applicable.
Then what about the address?
Yeomcheon Bridge, Gyeongseong...
Ah, wait a minute.
See if the Boss is there.
Hurry.
He's not here.
Since they've gathered them all together and put them in one address.
They'll be dragged away without a choice.
I guess I don't have to worry about my hair anymore.
If all the beggars from Yeomcheon Bridge and Yeongcheon gather, there'll be about 60 or 70 of them.
This is a really good thing.
It's not that great of a thing.
Sending dirty beggars to the National Defense Corps is a disgrace to the empire.
It may be a disgrace to the empire, but...
For those beggar punks, it's an honor they couldn't even dream of.
Of course.
Those who would have starved to death can now die gloriously for the empire.
In that case...
Let's just load up that Anchovy punk and his cronies onto the draft train.
You and I can stretch our legs and get some sleep.
That's right.
If the higher-ups find out we've dragged in even those without a clan, things could get noisy, so handle it quietly.
Don't worry.
Hey, man!
What are you doing out there, you cowards!
Get in here, man!
Stop messing around!
Get in there, man!
Hey, man, I told you I'd take care of everything. Why are you crying like a little girl?
It's because the Boss isn't here.
The Boss would know what to do in a situation like this.
What does he know?
The Boss is in a tight spot himself right now.
When the Boss isn't around, I'm the one who takes care of everything.
What do you know?
What are you going to do?
Hey, are you going to go?
I'm thinking, man.
Still, we have to meet the Boss and get his permission to go to the draft.
Hey, you ignorant fool.
It's not like you won't go just because the Boss says not to.
In times like this, our educated runaway...
If the Boss says not to go, I won't go even if I die.
Do you ask for the Boss's permission when you take a dump?
What's the same about going to the draft and taking a dump?
You have to do both even if you don't want to.
What's the same?
If you go to the draft, you die. If you don't go, you die. But if you take a dump, you're fine. If you don't, you're fine.
You're saying it's fine if you take a dump or not?
If you don't take a dump, you die.
How do you live 365 days a year without taking a dump?
I can, I can.
Do you know you'll die if you don't take a dump?
I can.
Shut up.
If you hold it in, you'll be in big trouble.
Stop talking about shit.
You said you'd take care of it.
Tell me what you're going to do.
This is what we'll do.
Hurry up and tell me what you're going to do.
Will you just shut up? I'm trying to tell you.
We all...
...run to Inwangsan.
Is that your plan?
You've been thinking all day in this rainy shack, and all you came up with is running to Inwangsan?
There's not a single hiding place with all these people around.
There's no point in idiots putting their heads together.
Okay, okay.
I have another idea.
Hey, give that here.
We all...
...stay put.
We're not going anywhere.
What kind of freezing prison is this for a beggar?
What if they come with guns and knives?
We'll think about that when it happens.
Yeah, you handle it well.
Do it well.
You're a birdbrain.
If you ask the Boss, it'll be solved right away.
Then why don't you tell me, man?
Are you the only bird, Crow?
Crows are birds too, man.
Do you have any special talents?
Tell me, tell me, man.
I think it would be best to meet Kim Du-han and Lee Myung-do.
They've probably faced a similar problem, so they might have found a solution.
Yeah, that's it.
That's exactly what I was thinking.
The metal fly was caught hiding under the millstone.
What about Hammer?
Hammer was on his way to his hometown when he was captured by the military police.
Half of the guys who got draft notices are in hiding, and it looks like the Japanese are trying to wipe out all the young men in Jongno.
Order some red bean porridge.
Boiling hot, enough to burn the roof of your mouth.
Give me a bowl of hot red bean porridge.
What do you mean, one bowl?
Order by the pair.
Bring me a cup.
Yes.
Sir, everyone's been dragged away and Jongno is empty. If those Japanese bastards push their way in...
How much does it cost to bury someone these days?
Pardon?
About 100 won should do it.
If we all empty our pockets, we should have that much.
Who died?
Me, you punk.
I'm going to have a showdown with that Abe guy.
If they keep taking our kids...
I'll kill that bastard and then I'll die too.
Du-han, we've got a big problem.
The beggars are all going to be drafted.
Sit down and eat some red bean porridge.
Red bean porridge is good, but...
The draft is a more urgent matter...
I told you to eat.
Yes.
Just go.
Is that a brothel?
You just go?
Why would I go?
If you can avoid it, you should.
Avoid what you can.
Huh?
Hey, can you stop the rain?
Can you stop the lightning?
There are things you can't control.
If you go, you die.
You won't die, man.
Even if you go into a tiger's den, you'll survive if you keep your wits about you.
This is several times worse than going into a tiger's den.
Cannonballs are flying all over the place. How can you dodge them?
If you can't dodge them, the cannonballs will.
Why would they target a beggar when there are so many important people around?
Don't talk so carelessly just because it's not your problem.
Whether it's someone else's problem or mine, it's better to give up on things that are impossible early on.
That's what's smart.
Hey, Kim Du-han.
I was going to meet you anyway, so it's good you came today.
Sit down, sit down.
Stop taking my kids.
I'm a very ignorant man.
If you keep acting like this, I won't just stand by.
The Sapa-ri that was captured the other day is the only son for three generations.
How can this be?
Even if you take them, they're useless troublemakers. Why are you so persistent...
That's exactly why I wanted to meet you.
I'm planning to create a special group for you and your men.
What is it?
The National Defense Guard.
Everyone except those who have already been drafted will participate.
What do they do there?
In the current situation, there's no distinction between the front and rear lines.
Even in the rear, you have to fight and serve just like on the front lines.
I'm good at fighting, but I'm terrible at serving...
If you don't want to serve, you can go get drafted and live or die as you please.
The National Defense Guard will be doing labor service at military factories and workshops near Gyeongseong.
While you're at it, can't you include the kids who are about to be drafted and the beggar kids?
People who have already received their draft notices can't be included.
Since we've put similar guys in one place, it'll be easier to control the mood and prevent trouble.
Of course.
If the situation worsens, they're the most likely to become a disloyal force, so we need to keep a close eye on them.
Yes, don't worry.
We're at war right now.
If a problem arises, we can just issue a mobilization order, drag them all to a mountain, and finish them off.
Yes, hello... hello?
Yes.
Ah, yes.
I understand.
I'm sorry to bother you.
Yes.
But...
Bring Chunsam.
Yes.
What did you come here to do?
Look at this guy's face, covered in fists.
You should have hit him with a bone.
Where's your turf?
Pardon?
I said, where is your territory?
Who are you under?
I'm not under anyone, just on my own...
Yes.
Look at me carefully.
Don't you know me?
I don't think I do.
You know Sucheol-ri, right?
I'm Wang-ho of Sucheol-ri.
I've never heard of you.
Ah, this guy is completely...
Hey.
Double-Blade and Du-han of Jongno.
Haryong of Myeongdong.
Gulbi-ppyeo of Yeongdeungpo.
And is there anywhere I don't know?
Where did you say you're from?
Where's your turf?
I live in Yeomcheon Bridge.
Yeomcheon... you're from Yeomcheon Bridge?
Ah, this guy...
Then you must know who's there.
You must know Chunsam.
Chunsam.
That guy who dries cheeks has a lot of guts.
It must have been huge there.
I was very hungry.
I raised him there.
You've heard a lot about Chunsam, right?
Chunsam.
Yes.
I'm Chunsam.
What did I just say?
I'm Kim Chunsam.
What?
You're Chunsam?
Yes.
Show me some proof.
Hey, you have to let people sleep.
Do you beat people up in the middle of the night?
Come out here.
Ah, I really...
Not that, it's Kim Chunsam.
Hey, Chunsam.
You have to endure it.
A Joseon beggar lives by his guts and dies by his guts.
You have to endure it even if it hurts.
What do I do? The second day hurts the most.
Endure it.
Grit your teeth and endure it.
I...
I can't do anything because he's a person I really like.
Let's go together, Chunsam.
Please.
Huh?
Please save our kids!
What's going to happen to me?
Should I just get my eye gouged out?
Why are you like this, you bastard!
Hey, you know a thing or two.
Do you know my father?
If you don't know the general in Joseon, are you even a Joseon person?
That guy must be sent to prison.
[PTT] Subtitles by knoe.ai
Precise Translation & Timing