Chunsam!
Kim Du-han?
You're dead today.
You are so dead by my hands today.
Come here!
Do you know who I am?
I'm Dokkae of Namdaemun.
You're Kim Du-han?
You're dead today.
Bring it on.
Precise [STT] by knoe.ai
Subtitles_Translations_Timing
A bit fast.
Yeah.
Ma'am!
Seems a little fast.
Are you laughing?
For real?
Now you're really dead.
You're dead now.
Didn't hit me.
I just fell.
He's losing his strength.
What are you guys doing?
Where is this?
Huh?
Is this Jongno?
Is this Namdaemun?
No, that's not it. We were on our way
to Namdaemun and just stopped by...
If you were on your way to Namdaemun, then just keep going.
Don't cause any trouble.
Actually, I was planning to visit you and pay my respects, sir...
You just stay in your own turf and
live well. That's all the greeting I need.
Go.
Yes.
And you.
Are you some back-alley mutt?
I asked if you're a mutt.
If you fight with a guy like that, you become a mutt too.
A mutt.
Do well, man.
Alright, let's go.
Let's go have some more fun.
Come here, come here.
Who are they?
They're from Hyuyanggak. All the
pretty girls in the city are gathered there.
Follow those girls.
What's the use of being pretty?
It's all pie in the sky.
Still, they must eat well. Their faces are glowing.
Hey, what are you doing?
Hurry up, man.
An engagement present.
It's the strongest and most beautiful thing in the world.
Do you know what it is?
Liberty, my love.
For you, I would give my life.
But, my love.
For liberty, I would give even you.
A patriotic poet from Hungary wrote it. What do you think, Han-young?
Are you serious about this, Min-jae?
Do you regret it?
Not once.
Are you scared?
Don't worry.
I'll hold your hand until the very end.
I'll ask you one more time.
Are you serious about this, Min-jae?
Hey, which one is it that you, the political Pollack, want?
That one, that one.
I thought the leather had gone into your hat, but it
seems there's still something visible in your eye holes.
Sis, if I wear that, won't I look like that
actor from the motion pictures back then?
No.
What do you think you'll look more like?
A Yeomcheon Bridge beggar.
Stop with the nonsense. I'll keep watch, so you go in and get it.
You go, sis.
I'll keep watch.
Hey, this way, this way.
Sis, sis.
Are your legs okay?
Yeah, they're fine.
Damn mutt.
This is really cool.
Hey, it's a bit old, but it's a good Western-style suit.
If I wear this, I'll look way cooler than that actor guy.
There's only one man in the world who would look good in this outfit.
None.
You mean the son of the Mishikoshi department store owner?
While I was singing a folk song, he kept staring
at my face so hard it felt like it would get a scratch.
When someone's singing, who are they supposed to look at?
The liquor bottle?
No, no, that's not it. He definitely thinks of me as special.
When he's with his friends, he talks just fine,
but when I sit next to him, he keeps stuttering.
He doesn't just do that with you.
He stutters in front of any woman.
Really?
Yeah.
One time, while I was serving
him burnt-rice water, I pinched the
back of his hand, and he spilled
it all over his expensive silk pants.
Really?
Right in the middle, too.
So?
I wiped it all off for him with a silk handkerchief.
Thoroughly.
Jin-young, what happened to those expensive
suit pants he ruined with the burnt-rice water?
Did you wash them?
No, he's rich. What are some silk pants to him?
He doesn't have money.
His father has a lot of money.
There's something I absolutely must teach you two today.
What is it?
Today, you'll learn for real.
Learn what?
How great money is.
Hey, but only loafers like this come here.
Man, I wonder if it's okay. Double-Blade might be here.
I've never been here before...
Du-han, what's wrong?
You have to play where the big shots are.
The three of us will team up and get rid of Dokkae.
We'll take over everything from Jingogae to Jangchungdan!
What do you think?
Right, Chunsam?
Yeah.
Follow me!
Is anyone there?
Hey... is anyone home?
Hmm?
Du-han of Jongno is here for a drink!
Enjoy your meal.
Uh-huh.
Alright!
It's done!
Hey, relax your shoulders and sit down.
I've got the owner of this place completely wrapped around my finger.
A pretty girl named Gye-hyang will be coming in.
Huh?
Hey, what for?
She'll pour our drinks... so what's wrong with that?
It's better to have a pretty girl, my friend.
If you're going to drink, it's better to
have something nice to look at, right?
Come on.
A girl is just a girl.
She doesn't have to be that pretty. Just
meet up occasionally and relieve some stress.
Hey, I have to go first.
What's wrong?
We haven't even finished talking about stabbing Dokki's underling!
Let's talk about that later.
Man, later is later, and now is now!
Hey, where are you going?
You have to eat this and go.
Hey, a guy who used to
roll around in a shack is now
sitting in a place like this,
my butt's starting to get sore.
Hey!
Hey, hey, Chunsam!
Hey, with this, our kids can go to Seoul.
We're having a big feast tonight.
Hey, what's wrong with you?
Sit down.
Hey, I ate well. I'm leaving.
Hey, hey, come here!
Hey, stop!
Oh my, oh my, oh my.
A year of reverse vegetables, and one
person is specially taken care of in the kitchen.
I came to see you today.
Ah,
Tongs.
Hey!
Oh, of course.
Well, if it isn't Mr. Kim of Yeomcheon Bridge, where have you been?
Hey, if it wasn't for me, would you ever
have come to a place like this in your life?
Thanks to you, I really did come to a nice place.
Yeah, it'll be a night you'll never forget.
If you want to make it an unforgettable night, do me one favor.
What?
Over there, the picture taken at the big drinking party.
Who is the dancing lady?
You mean Haewol.
Call that woman for me.
Hey, hey, just drink.
Once you strip a woman down, they're all the same.
Call her.
It'll only take a moment.
You dream big.
How can you call a girl who is entertaining the
high-ranking officials from the Government-General?
Hyeongdo, please.
Let's just drink, huh?
Don't worry.
What was her name?
Haewol or Gaewol?
I'll call her for you.
Oh!
Madam, I know this is difficult, but...
I have a favor to ask.
There's an order to socializing.
Besides, first impressions are very important.
No, just a brief greeting, and then I'll...
There's a proper way to do things, President Im.
No, I've wanted to meet the elders of
the Government-General for a while.
Especially Abe of Jongno Police Station, huh?
I have a lot of business to see Abe-nari about...
That's right, President Im.
It's not proper to barge in and ask to meet
high-ranking Japanese officials after only two meetings.
Especially without a prior appointment.
Ah, well, then I guess there's nothing I can do.
Well, then, since it's a shame,
please call out that girl in
the room, Haewol or whatever
her name is, for a moment.
That's not a difficult request, is it?
If it's your date of birth...
What...
Your birth date and time, I mean.
Ah... how would I know that?
You?
Ah, I've been wandering around since I was
a kid, how would I know something like that?
Mr. Kim, that's really...
No, why do you need to know that anyway?
The madam's greatest hobby is reading people's fortunes.
First, she looks at your face, and if she
thinks you're going to be big, she treats you well.
What a crappy hobby.
What would a beggar know about that?
Here, have a drink, Mr. Kim.
What's wrong?
Anyway, if you don't know your
fortune, it's hard to see that girl's face?
Hey, are you that Gaewol... no, hey, are you Haewol?
I, I don't know.
Hey, have you been here before?
I'm... I'm Mr. Kim from Yeomcheon Bridge...
Hey, wait, just wait a minute.
A long time ago in Daegu...
The madam told me to write down your fortune and send it to her.
Surely the children of high-ranking
officials wouldn't be ignorant of their fortunes...
If their fortunes aren't clear, she said to show
her your palm after the drinking party is over.
Giminy-eon, March 1st, noon.
That's a pure dog's fortune.
Your birth date is all wrong, you bastard.
Your palm, your palm.
Even Park Bosal said you were destined to live by your fists.
There's nothing good about it.
What more is there to fight for?
You're so great.
I don't know what's so great about you.
Anyway, you're great.
What did he say earlier?
That you were fated to be a beggar and a saint?
Ugh, it's complicated.
Ugh, what a beggar-like guy.
Still, I'm the best.
If it wasn't for me, when would you two ever
get to drink at a thousand-won charcoal fire?
You guys heard that, right?
Dohwasal, Dohwasal.
Yes, he said I would be very successful if I worked in motion pictures.
I'm going to own the biggest theater in
Joseon and only show movies I've made.
Then I'll let you two watch for free every day.
For free!
Hey, you take care of this.
You guys go down first.
Hey, where are you going?
Chunsam, I'm telling you, she's not Gaewol.
Hey, you're confusing her with another girl.
Excuse me.
Just a moment, I need to check something.
Don't block me.
Excuse me.
You really don't know me?
A long time ago in Daegu, when those
Japanese gangster punks stole my fountain pen.
Daegu?
Yes, those Japanese judo kids.
That time, I got your fountain pen back for you.
Do you remember?
When I came to your house back then, you gave me food.
Ah, then that beggar from back then...
Yes, that's right.
So you do remember.
Now in Gyeongseong...
Yes, I came up to Gyeongseong and
I'm doing some business here and there...
Wow, you remember.
That time in front of the rice mill, I
got your fountain pen back for you...
So what about it?
I remember, but there's no need to remember it again, is there?
Haewol, hurry up and come in.
Please be careful on your way.
Boss!
What are you doing there?
I said, what are you doing here?
Well, some rich idiot threw this away.
So I picked it up.
Hey, we should all gather and share something like this.
Since we can't tear it apart, just wear it, Boss.
It looks like a fly, put it on.
No, no.
The Boss has to wear this.
Let's see.
You'll look so cool with this on.
I said it's okay.
My sister worked so hard to get this
for the Boss, how can you not wear it?
My sister almost got bitten to death by a dog while stealing this.
Didn't I tell you that you should never steal?
Didn't I say I'd kick you out of the shack if you ever steal again?
Is it okay for a girl to be running around stealing?
You can just throw it back in that house's yard right now.
Sis!
What did I do?
You heard him, right?
Yeah, the Boss is really mean.
So what if I brought back some pollack?
Not that.
He called me a girl.
So are you a boy, sis?
Look, do I look like a girl in any way?
But the Boss called me a girl.
I feel so sorry for you, sis.
By the way, are you really going to return this now?
I can't even collect my dues properly.
Oh, you idiot!
What is it?
This is the guy who's been hanging around
for days, saying he has to greet you, sir.
Nice to meet you.
I'm seeing you for the first time, but I've heard
your name so much it's made my ears bleed.
Is that so?
Not really.
Ever since I was a kid, I thought Dokkae
was the greatest man after Admiral Yi Sun-sin.
I've respected you for a long time.
How did you get here?
Being in front of you like this, my heart is pounding
like a girl in love. I can't express how good I feel.
Stop with the flattery and get to the point.
A few days ago, I heard you were disgraced because of that Anchovy punk.
So?
It's my wish to have a drink
over that bastard's corpse.
I'll take the lead in catching
and killing that Anchovy punk.
He's as stubborn as bamboo.
Just punch him hard in the stomach. What a bastard.
Yeon-ji, someone's here to see you.
Oh.
Yeon-ji, Ae-sim, how did you get here?
What about school?
Hey, that's great.
You're still the precious daughter of
a rich family, no matter where you go.
I'm not the precious daughter of a
rich family anymore, so don't say that.
It reminds me of my school days.
Are all the dancers doing well?
It's been three years since I came to Gyeongseong.
I can speak the Gyeongseong dialect well now.
You said you were attending a
professional school. What's it like these days?
Every day as soon as the sun
rises, we put on our leggings
and work pants, and do military
and anti-communist training.
How's my Gyeongseong accent?
Oh, you girl.
You should have told me earlier.
It's cold inside.
What?
What did you just say?
Do you have to take a test to become a gisaeng?
No matter how hard school is, it's better than being a gisaeng.
It's not that I want to wear fancy clothes and makeup like you.
My father is trying to marry me off to the eldest son of a mill owner.
You know how much I hate that pimple-faced guy, right?
Whenever he sees me, he grins with those yellow teeth.
Just seeing the back of his neck gives me goosebumps.
But still...
Wouldn't it be better to just hang myself than
to marry a guy like that and live a miserable life?
I ran away from home to die.
But I thought it would be better to be a gisaeng
than to die, so I came to you for help, Yeon-ji.
You only live once and die once,
but I really don't want to live like this.
I'm a woman too, and I'm young. Shouldn't
I at least get to bloom once before I die?
The flower of youth?
That kind of flower doesn't even sprout in a gisaeng house.
I'm not doing this because I like it.
I'll only be a gisaeng for three years,
and after that, I'll live doing what I want.
A gisaeng is a gisaeng.
It's different from other women.
Gisaengs wear their skirts tied to the right like this.
Do you know what this means?
It means anyone can lift your skirt.
As long as they have money.
Do you understand now?
Do you still like it?
Do you still want to be a gisaeng?
Yes.
I want to be like Hwang Jin-yi.
Yes, I hate the idea of
getting married and living a
miserable life looking at only one
man's face for the rest of my life.
Like Hwang Jin-yi, I want to
live a fiery life, breaking the
will of meditating monks and
making arrogant men cry. Yes.
You were born with the fate of a courtesan.
You're completely different from her.
Where did you bring a girl like this from?
Ae-sim and I have been best friends since we were little.
I don't know what you'll think
of her at first, but if you spend
time with her, you'll soon see
that she's a really good person...
Haewol, you weren't originally
fated to be a gisaeng, you're
just passing through, but she's
the complete opposite of you.
That's right.
She and I have always been opposites since we were kids.
You need to fix your way of speaking first.
Pardon?
Your dialect.
I can speak the Gyeongseong dialect well.
You haven't seen each other in a while,
why don't you go out and get some fresh air?
But tonight there's an important engagement...
From now on, you'll be tied down anyway,
so I'm giving you special time off today.
That's great.
A new movie starring Moon Ye-bong
is playing at Umigwan. Let's go see it.
It would be nice if you could come with us, ma'am.
The instruments?
Is the performance ready?
Are you still scared?
I trust you, Han-hyuk.
Why?
I'm not confident.
No.
Be confident.
You have to be confident.
I got this new from the Soviets.
It's very accurate.
And there are three extra rounds.
Leave the bag and get out immediately.
You know how powerful the gunpowder is, right?
Don't worry about me. Just wait by the
river until nightfall, and a carriage will come.
Change carriages at the intersection
and go straight to the pier in Incheon.
When you get to the pier...
I know to look for a boat with a red flag on its mast.
Min-ja.
If by some chance something goes wrong...
Even if you say that...
We have to prepare.
Min-jeong, you did well.
I need to go left.
Hurry!
Oh, I think I'm going to throw up from the smell of alcohol.
Damn, what the hell happened?
What's this?
Hey!
Do you want me to watch you drink?
Have you seen a tall guy?
No.
Did you see him?
I didn't see him.
Hurry up and clean up, man.
Aren't we doing something pointless?
We don't know where this dog bone came from.
We don't know where this dog bone came from either.
Thank you.
Sis, let's give this to Grasshopper hyung and get something to eat.
No.
The Boss told us not to bother him.
Do you know why the shoes I shine don't shine?
Why?
Is Grasshopper hyung here?
Yeah.
Look.
It's because my spit is thin.
You're supposed to use spit more than polish when you
shine shoes, but since I only eat garbage porridge, huh?
My spit is thin.
And no matter how much I shine them, they don't seem to shine?
It's so unfair to eat the same thing.
Sis!
Hey, Crow!
Damn it, you!
Hey!
You wanna die!
Ah, Crow!
Grasshopper hyung!
What are you doing?
There's a lot.
Ah, this, this.
Should we go back inside?
Oppa, I'll take some wood.
Hand, hand, hand, hand!
Hand, hand, hand!
Sir, I'll clean this up for you.
Okay.
Oh, that's just for Yeomcheon Bridge. Why did you come here?
She's one of Chunsam's girls.
Is that so?
I can't tell if this is a boy or a girl just by looking at the face.
You'll have to go to the bathhouse.
You'll have to roll around for about
three days to get the old dirt off, huh?
Damn it!
Ah!
You disrespectful...
This bastard!
Hey!
Hey, grab her face!
Hey, do we have to gag her?
What if she bites her tongue and dies?
You bastard, why, why would she bite her tongue?
Hey, it's okay, it's okay.
Stay quiet.
Hey, hold her tight!
I'm going in!
I'm going in, hold her tight!
Hey, hold her tight!
Hold her tight!
Hey, grab her shoulders, shoulders, shoulders!
Hey, grab her shoulders!
I let go, I let go, I let go!
It's out!
Because of something this small, people live and die...
Hey, bring me something to burn.
Bring the fire first, the fire!
Hey, bring the fire!
Hey, grab the noodles.
Hey, you're alive, man.
Hold tight, hold tight!
Hey, hold tight!
Is it done?
She fainted from the fire.
Hey, bring the charcoal.
Hey, get some water.
The Boss's skills are no joke. He cut the flesh in a
cross shape, put his finger in, and the bullet came out.
But what if the wound gets infected?
You bastard, I'm using charcoal right now.
It'll be fine because it's charcoal.
This is a matter of life and death, so I'm saying
this. I could go to the hospital and steal some...
Hey, what is it, man?
Hey, what happened?
Young master!
Young... young, young master!
Young master, what are you doing in a place like this...
So, is he the son of that rich family where you used to be a servant?
Uh, uh.
He's covered in blood.
Did he have a major surgery?
Boss, what happened to our young master?
I don't know, man.
Ask your young master.
I'm getting some water right now.
These kids are getting some water.
Blood!
Boss, what's wrong?
Why are you avoiding me?
Hey, what's wrong with your face?
It's nothing.
Hey, I'm asking you what happened.
I said it's nothing!
I went to the King Star, and I got hit by a new underling of Dokkae.
Was Dokkae there?
Yes.
My sister beat up the guy who hit me.
Who's Dokkae's underling?
Well, he's a really ugly guy.
So, what's his name?
He's the guy who got hit by a dog, and I think Dokkae called him Toe.
Right, right?
Yeah.
What?
Toe... Toe?
You mean Toe from Daegu came to Gyeongseong?
Are you sure it was Toe?
Yes, that's what Dokkae said.
I don't care if it's Toe or a finger,
I'm fine, so why do you keep asking?
Where is he now?
I said I'm fine!
Where is he!
He... he said he was going to Umigwan.
He said he was going to see a movie...
Huh?
Boss!
Don't go!
Don't you guys ever kiss?
You've been holding hands for a while now. I'm
going to die without seeing you two eat a wedding cake.
Yeah, just watch them do their thing.
You don't even know you're about to fall off a cliff.
If it's too much, just give up.
By the way, where is that delicious smell coming from?
That's right, sir.
You have a sharp nose.
Is this the smell of sesame oil...
or castor oil...
There's a bean smell coming from someone.
Ladies!
Why do you want to step in dog poop and get hurt?
Because I stepped in dog poop!
What?
That...
The right one is the left one.
No matter how you look at it, can you tell
the difference between weasel fur and pig fur?
Even the right one...
I'll have her in your arms tonight, so just stay put.
I was just about to say hello, but it's a shame you're leaving.
Sir, how many rickshaws should I call?
Just one should be enough.
Hey!
Why are you here?
I came to see a movie.
Didn't I tell you not to drink, watch
movies, or even pass through Jongno?
Do you own this place?
Does a stray dog have to get your permission to take a dump here?
Yeah, maybe not people, but stray
dogs and punks like you need permission.
Hey!
Hey,
Du-han, Du-han.
You saw Dokkae?
Where is he?
I don't know.
I'm busy right now.
Come on.
Where's that dog-eyed Toe?
He's dead, you bastard.
Du-han!
Anchovy.
It's been a while.
Let that woman go.
I have important business with her.
Let her go now.
You haven't changed a bit, even after all this time.
It's great to see you after such a long time.
If you leave, it'll be a great...
Let's go, Yeon-ji.
Are you okay?
Du-han!
Kim Du-han!
That's enough now.
I'll be going.
No, it's still dangerous.
I'll take you to where I live.
I'm fine.
This neighborhood...
It's more complicated than it looks.
There are good people, and people from Namdaemun,
and even people from Wangsimni coming and going...
Anyway, I'll take you to where I live.
No.
There's no need for that.
I won't feel at ease otherwise.
In that case, I'd like to buy you a cup of tea to show my gratitude.
Do you like coffee?
Yes.
He passed away in Tokyo.
Mr. Yi Sang.
Yi Sang?
That's a strange name.
He was a strange person, just like his name.
He was originally an architect, but he also wrote poetry, painted...
He seems to have been a very talented poet.
A poet?
Yes.
Welcome.
His poems are as unique as he was.
They're a bit difficult, but if you keep
reading them, you start to understand...
Do you like poetry?
Pardon?
Yes.
Poetry...
That's a song I like.
What song is it?
"The Lonely Streetlight."
I used to think I was a very special person.
Sad and unfortunate things...
I lived believing they would all avoid me.
Until I was seventeen.
But that wasn't the case.
Misfortune struck suddenly.
From the moment my father started playing mahjong.
Mahjong...
Gambling ruins everything.
Our house...
Our orchard, everything was lost...
And he left for Manchuria.
He sold all our cotton blankets in the winter...
Seeing my younger siblings shivering all
night under the remaining thin blankets...
I thought I had to do something, anything.
Anything...
So you went to the Huian store...
This time, I'll make sure you can hold on to the train.
The pure spirit of the Great Japanese Empire commands the Korean will...
Are you crazy?
You're the crazy one.
Can I visit you again?
Pardon?
Can I come see you again?
Let's meet again.
Didn't I tell you that you should never hit me?
I never thought the day would come when
I'd take off my clothes in front of you, sir.
Precise [STT] by knoe.ai
Subtitles_Translations_Timing