Fine.
I'm going back in.
Listen up.
Gimbap and Parrot, follow me.
Gimbap and I will go and get that woman from her room.
Parrot, you take care of the emergency room.
Boss, what about this woman?
Hold her.
[PTT] Subtitles by knoe.ai
Precise Translation & Timing
This isn't good.
His temperature is dropping and his pulse is getting faster.
I'm moving him back to the emergency room.
Why is this guy so unstable?
I think he's going into secondary shock...
Dr. Wang, I need your help.
Dr. Wang?
Yes?
Yes.
She must be crazy!
What!
It's a fake, it's a fake!
What do we do!
Get her on the bed!
This bitch!
Hurry up!
Kill her!
Stop it.
That's why we need to treat her quickly.
Calm down!
Where did he go?
He has nowhere to go!
Call the discharge office, quickly!
This guy's going to crack his head open!
Quickly!
Call!
An epilepsy patient came in on his own.
Just give him about 2mm of Valium first.
We tried that, but it's not working well.
Give him 2mm more.
Yes, understood.
Man, it's been a long time.
What... what is it?
Get him in, get him in quick.
What about the stupid woman?
Tell her to go alone.
Yeah, she says she's going.
Idiot, what about Parrot?
He's taking care of things, he'll be out soon.
Hey guys!
Give me a piggyback ride.
Hye-wol's room is over there.
The party won't be over for a while. What should we do?
There's nothing to worry about.
I'll wait until the night is over.
Then shall I keep you company?
There's no need to waste time.
I'm not a bee that lands on just any flower.
Who asked you to touch me?
I just offered to be your companion.
Just take the gift and leave.
This is disgustingly delicious.
Hey, you, Gimbap.
Get him inside before anyone sees.
Hey, Hama.
Yes.
Left Foot.
Burn it.
Hey, where did Raccoon go?
Raccoon!
Thank you.
You saved both of our lives.
Money isn't important, but this debt I will never...
Money is important.
I'll try to get it as soon as possible.
Let's just save him first.
The Boss is a strange person.
He's not a philosopher, nor a revolutionary.
Let's talk about the complicated stuff later, just take him inside.
Hey, Raccoon!
Hey, where did Raccoon go?
Boss.
Um, my sister is gone.
Where did she go?
Where could she have gone besides home?
She'll be back soon.
No, Boss.
I think she went to cause trouble...
Something must have happened.
Huh?
What happened?
Hey, don't just stand there making me frustrated, tell me quickly.
She must have gone to the gisaeng house.
What, the gisaeng house?
Why the gisaeng house?
You tell me, man.
Well, earlier today...
I mentioned the gisaeng.
Hey, I told you to guard the shack well.
Hey, Raccoon, what were you doing?
Hey, the shack is fine.
It's just that Crow has lost her mind.
Hey, you two, guard them well.
The Boss is mine.
Boss, Boss.
I've been waiting for three hours today.
I never asked you to wait.
For a busy man like me, three hours is like several days for an ordinary person.
Do you have any idea how much I've invested in you?
I hope that today was worth the wait.
Well...
I'm sorry, but I don't think it will be.
Joseon women may not have the gentle charm of Japanese women, but they have a sharp, witty appeal that I quite like.
Please leave.
Hey.
What are you doing?
Haewol.
Let go.
Do you know how long I've waited for you?
What are you doing?
You insolent wench.
How dare you do this to me?
Hey.
Let go.
No, Chunsam.
Stop.
Stop right there.
No.
Chunsam.
Stop it.
No.
That bastard deserves to die.
He deserves to die.
Stop it.
Yeon-hee.
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
Chunsam.
You're bleeding.
Yeon-hee.
I'll kill anyone who lays a hand on Yeon-hee.
Let's go.
Forward.
Do you want to go home?
Yes.
There's no one here.
Pardon?
A Japanese guy.
This is a big problem.
It's not a big problem at all.
I just poked him a little.
Don't you know?
He's following us again.
Hey, do you know what the hardest thing in the world is?
The hardest thing in the world is a human head.
I don't know who made it, but it's really hard.
Hurry, hurry, hurry.
How can we live here?
It's so cold in here.
It's okay.
Boss.
If you sleep here until dawn, you'll be a frozen pollack.
Hey, Grasshopper.
If it freezes, it becomes a frozen pollack. If it thaws, it becomes a dried pollack. If you starve for a few days, it becomes a dried pollack. That's how all beggars live.
Rain.
In the rainy street
In the lonely street
How can I forget those old days when you made me cry and left?
They broke Min-jae out of the hospital.
With the help of the people here.
Where is this?
Under the Yeomcheon Bridge.
A slum?
It's worse than that.
It's a beggar's shack.
Don't worry.
I'll take you somewhere else.
To a comfortable and safe place.
You can get treatment there.
I'm fine.
Yes... it doesn't matter where I am.
As long as we can be together like this...
It doesn't matter where I am.
You crazy fool!
Stop rubbing your face all over the floor!
When a bride and groom meet after a long time, we have to see if sparks fly or if it's just a dud, you beggar punks.
The young master is setting the mood, why don't you come over here?
You sickly beggar punks!
Hurry, hurry!
Or I'll break your legs!
Hurry!
Hey, hurry!
You go too!
No, now... now...
Eat.
It's a calming pill.
It's okay.
Why?
You take that when you're scared.
I'm not scared right now, I'm angry and frustrated.
I'm angry that I was born a woman, and frustrated that I have to keep living as a woman.
Why were women created to be so pathetic?
We don't have the strength to protect our own bodies.
But you're pretty.
Not rough and tough like men.
It's just a shame that you're a little weak.
Even though we're in the same boat, it's cheap to think of using your face as a weapon against men.
That's all we have.
Hey, if a pretty girl wags her tail and seduces a man,
even the strongest man will fall for it.
If I were just a little prettier, I could have a man among men like Du-han in the palm of my hand...
You should never expect true love from people who live by their fists.
You'll only get hurt.
Kim Chunsam is a gangster who hangs out with Du-han.
Chunsam is not a gangster.
Do you think I'd be seeing him if he were the kind of person who just goes around swinging his fists for fun?
But I really don't know if that person is a human or a ghost.
He got hit in the head with a shovel and was bleeding, but he didn't even flinch.
What's going to happen to him now?
The police are searching Gyeongseong like a flea comb. He's bound to get caught.
What do we do?
I don't know.
Let's go in.
Hey, what's this?
Hey, what's wrong, Ae-sim?
Mom!
Hey, I should call a servant from the main house to beat them and kick them out.
Wait a minute.
You must have been very hungry.
Still, you shouldn't just barge into someone else's house.
Don't do it again.
Okay?
Here, take this and eat it.
Take it.
Hmm?
You mean girl.
She's so pretty, even the Boss must have fallen for her.
A girl like me is not even a woman, nothing.
Hey.
Where have you been?
Do you know how long I've been looking for you?
Who told you to wait for me here all night?
Let's go inside.
I told you not to wait for me there all night...
What's wrong with you?
Have you been drinking?
You idiot.
You and I are both idiots, you idiot.
What are you talking about, coming in drunk in the middle of the night?
Just as the Boss doesn't even sniff at me no matter how much I bark, do you think I'll even bat an eye if you throw a fit?
You fool.
What's so great about an idiot like me?
Crow, you know.
To me, you are a longing.
We live together in the same shack every day, so what's there to miss?
I don't want to be your longing.
How can I not miss you?
I see you staring at the Boss every day until your eyes pop out like a toad's. Just thinking about you breaks my heart.
I'm a person too.
Once in a while, for a change of pace, look at me too.
You fool.
I can live without eating, but I can't live a single day without thinking about the Boss.
If the Boss marries another woman...
Do you think I'll just stand by?
I'll kill those women, kill the Boss, and then kill myself.
Even if you marry another man, I can't kill you.
How could I kill someone as fragile as a blade of grass?
It's better for me to die alone.
Police, police, police... what, are you looking for the police?
What about the examination hall?
How is it?
I went out, I went out, I went out.
I don't know, I don't know.
But Boss, this isn't a safe place.
Hey, this looks really delicious.
Welcome.
Are you Yoomyungdo?
Yes, that's right.
Follow me.
No, I need to know what's going on before I can go.
Hey, what's wrong?
Sir.
Just watch the store.
Get that rope, you bastard.
No, so...
Did you sell a lot?
What?
Didn't I tell you to just go on your own and not follow me?
There's a gisaeng who saw you two come in together, yet you keep playing dumb.
Just a guy you met on the street and had a drink with? Who is he and what does he do?
Even if you're close, if you don't know, you don't know.
I get that you didn't see him and don't know him.
Hey, tell me.
Who is he and what does he do?
You have to untie him to make him talk.
Tell me.
I am...
Fine.
Is the teacher outside?
Teacher.
Why?
Sir.
I don't know anything, but I'm innocent.
My only crime is working hard to make a living.
But why are you doing this?
I pay my taxes well.
I'm good to the police and I'm a first-class citizen of the Japanese Empire.
I have something to tell you.
So cooperate.
Who is that guy?
I don't even know who he is.
I told you, he's just some beggar I met on the street.
A beggar?
That guy is a beggar?
I'm not saying he's really a beggar, I'm saying his clothes are like a beggar's.
That's right.
His clothes are like a beggar's and he looks like a beggar.
Tell me clearly.
Is that guy a beggar or not?
I'm telling you the truth.
I'm telling you, he's a real beggar.
I'm telling you, I only know how to make money.
Ask the beggars at Yeomcheon Bridge about him.
Jeong-don.
Sir.
That guy from Yeomcheon Bridge?
Yes.
It seems certain.
You've been through a lot.
I was already having a headache because of the Sung Min-jae escape incident, and now this has made things very difficult.
The situation is very bad, isn't it?
Good.
When things get this complicated, you're bound to meet in one place.
Somehow, this incident is definitely related to the attempted assassination of Superintendent Endo.
I have a feeling.
No, then...
No.
Don't ask why.
I don't know either.
Where is the teacher?
Sir.
Singers are connected to each other.
If you dig deep enough, you'll find what you're looking for.
What should we do with that guy?
Let him go.
He's said what he needs to say.
Put a tail on him.
I'll tail him myself...
Sir.
Hey, you punk.
Is that girl that great?
A woman is medicine if you like her in moderation, but she's poison if you fall too hard.
You stupid fool.
You're going to ruin your life.
Do you have any hammers in your shop?
You'd have to go to a hardware store for that.
Get me one.
What for?
To nail your mouth shut.
You're a man, but you get scared by a little threat like that.
It's not that I wanted to tell him, it just came out...
What do you mean, you didn't know?
You're the one who told him everything.
Even if I hadn't told him, they would have found out soon enough.
Even so, is it the same as them finding out from somewhere else?
You're his friend.
Friend?
I can pretend to die for a friend, but I can't actually die.
If you can't actually die, then friend or not, it's nothing.
I can't do it.
If I had two or three lives, maybe, but I only have one.
Right.
Then cherish your one and only life.
Before someone takes it from you.
Hey, you bastard!
Aren't you going too far?
That's enough!
Find Jun-seo!
We have to find him before the police do!
We have to find him quickly and send him to some remote place.
We can't let him spend his youth in prison.
You beggar-like bastard!
Oh my!
I told you, Han-young.
Love was supposed to make us stronger.
But I guess that's not it.
I thought so when we were together.
But now that I'm alone, I feel myself getting weaker.
I'm sorry.
I ran away by myself, didn't I?
No, Han-young.
That's not what I meant...
That will never happen.
We'll always be together.
In life and in death.
Hey!
Aren't you guys worried?
You don't even know if the Boss who saved your lives is dead or alive, and you're just sitting here holding hands and chatting?
How do you know so well what men and women do when they meet?
I guess you're a woman too, sis.
Seeing you get jealous.
Shut up!
Wait, what happened?
Didn't he get caught by a robber, beaten up, and die?
Have you ever seen a robber do that?
When it's dark, you can't tell if it's a beggar or something else.
Don't be ridiculous.
He'd get robbed trying to rob the Boss.
He'd die, he'd die.
Hey!
They're here again.
Is your leader in there?
He's not here.
Yes.
He's really not here.
We've been looking for him all night.
All night.
There's only bedbugs and rat droppings here.
There's nothing here.
Our bean paste...
No meat either?
No.
There's nothing.
Did you search everywhere?
Yes.
I've searched everywhere, even the bean paste pot...
You really don't know where your leader is?
That's right.
We really don't know right now.
Don't say you don't know even if you do.
Who do you think I am?
You'll have to search the bean paste pot carefully.
If you're so pure...
Bring those two.
Yes.
No!
Let go!
Do-yeon.
Hama.
Gan-hee.
Do-yeon.
How did you know there was a doggy door here?
Min-jae.
Hey, Hama, this is bad.
Can you get a rickshaw?
Violence is not something to be used on people.
How much it must have hurt.
Even after being hurt like this, are you still not going to tell me where your Boss is?
We don't know.
How can we tell you what we don't know?
If you knew, you would have told me already.
It's true.
I really hate violence, but...
When this is the only way, there's no other choice.
Excuse me.
We might die anyway.
What kind of teacher is that?
Unlike others, we haven't lost our teeth, so our jaw muscles are weak.
Sir.
Yes.
Just being pretty and knowing how to pour drinks doesn't make you a gisaeng.
You have to smile in front of a customer who wants to laugh, and you have to cry in front of a customer who wants to see tears.
How dare you be rude to a customer you don't like?
Do you know the difference between a woman and a gisaeng?
A woman must be a person before she is a woman, and a gisaeng must be a woman before she is a person.
While you're a gisaeng, you have to throw away all the pride that ordinary people have.
There's a girl among you who, because of her pride, refuses to lower herself in front of men.
Keep that nature well hidden, and take it out again when you quit being a gisaeng and go back to being a woman.
Everyone, leave. Haewol, you stay.
You said you'd only be a gisaeng until you're twenty-two, right?
Yes.
Why?
By then, my younger siblings will be able to take care of themselves, and after that, I want to live for myself.
You're a very smart girl to be planning your life at such a young age.
But your plan requires you to earn a lot of money in a short period of time...
What will happen if every customer who sees you turns their back on you?
What are you talking about?
I'm talking about Director Ikeda.
You haven't even visited him once, have you?
You know that Director Ikeda is the Governor-General's nephew, right?
From now on, the people from the Governor-General's office won't be pleased with you.
I don't care.
I'm not pleased with him either.
It's a crude expression, but there's a difference between scary and dirty.
Even if I starve to death and my family ends up on the street, I can't go visit that man.
Madam, someone's here to see you.
You can't come in here.
Madam, that person just came in without thinking...
No.
This will be the first and last time I ask or demand anything of you.
I won't do this again.
Don't say that.
It's been so long.
I'm so happy that you came to see me.
Really?
I was so surprised when I heard you ran away from home.
From the person who left her eight-year-old child in that house and walked away?
That was all for you...
It was for me, wasn't it?
There was no thought for you, who lived as you pleased after leaving me behind. It was all for your young son from beginning to end, right?
I thought you would be happy in that house.
The things I couldn't give you, your father...
Stop it!
The news that you were growing up well.
The news that you had become a respectable student at Gyeongseong Medical School. I wanted to run to you more than a dozen times.
This mother has spent her whole life...
I don't plan on staying long.
As soon as I get a message from Shanghai and Min-jae's body has recovered enough, I'll take him away immediately.
Don't worry.
I'll take care of him with all my strength.
He's precious to me.
He's a comrade, a teacher, and like a mother to me. He's a very precious person, more than you can imagine.
Han-young.
Can't you call me 'mother' just once?
When you sold me to the Lee family of Samcheong-dong 14 years ago, my mother died.
Go out first.
Yes.
The madam told me to give you this.
I'm only taking 300 won.
Please return the rest.
Um...
Do you know where Chunsam is right now?
Chunsam...
You know the Boss?
Then maybe the one who gave the Boss the Yi Sang poetry collection...
Yes...
Could I possibly meet him?
Everyone at the shack is worried, but we don't have any news.
What should I do?
He's badly hurt.
He won't be safe if he's caught by the patrolmen.
Don't worry too much.
The Boss is not someone who will go down easily.
How can two women be so different?
Just as there are different sizes of loaches, from as big as an adult's finger to tiny ones, I guess all women are the same.
I'm sure my eyes are covered not with pollack skin, but with something thicker, like pig skin.
What should I do? I find Crow a thousand times prettier than that woman.
That's what happens when you like someone.
This is a hospital where one of two has to die to be cured.
Crow...
Yes.
You've been through a lot of trouble.
Not at all.
There are always a lot of people behind me.
Many women, many men.
But there are very few people I can ask for help.
People are the most precious thing to people, but it's all because I lack virtue.
Just tell me what I can do.
I'll help in any way I can.
Even if I suspect something, I won't tell anyone.
Don't worry.
I'm sorry.
Who are you?
Don't worry.
Han-young...
He went back to Yeomcheon Bridge.
He'll be safe there, so don't worry too much.
Where am I?
You should have some porridge...
What kind of place is this?
It's a gisaeng house.
And I'm a gisaeng who works in this house.
Everyone has their own way of living.
A noble lady, a servant girl, or a gisaeng...
Like it or not, I think it's better to sing and dance than to be dragged away as a comfort woman.
Am I making things difficult for you by asking unnecessary questions?
No.
Actually, I'm envious.
To dedicate your life to something more precious than just making a living, and also...
Pardon?
I'm envious that you can do the same work as the person you love.
How do you know Han-young?
I know someone at Yeomcheon Church.
Yeomcheon Church?
Yes.
Someone you like?
It's funny, isn't it?
A gisaeng meeting a beggar.
No.
What's so funny about it?
Can you understand?
Of course.
If it's true love, it doesn't matter what the man does for a living.
But it is a bit special.
That Anchovy punk is finished.
With the police all over the place, it's only a matter of time before he's caught, right?
You're going to get a windfall without even lifting a finger, sir.
The police are going to take care of that thorn in your side, Anchovy.
I thought you would be happy, sir.
What do you mean?
You hated Anchovy so much that you were always waiting for something bad to happen to him.
Why would I?
You really don't understand people, do you?
I'm the kind of person who hates getting things without working for them.
Look at that samurai Chan-chan.
Have you seen the movie or not?
He carried a knife in his heart for over 10 years to get revenge.
That guy.
If he gets taken down by someone else right in front of my eyes, how would I feel?
Then what should we do?
Whatever happens.
You have to find that guy before the police do.
Got it?
Sir.
Don't look, don't look.
Don't look.
Are you really sure?
There's no doubt about it.
I'm telling you, a cop is definitely following us.
Hey.
Don't cops have anything better to do?
Following around good citizens like us.
Where the hell is that Chunsam hiding?
What's so great that they're making such a fuss?
That's just how it is.
Does the outside world cry and laugh according to your mood?
They don't have to, but that's what friends do.
Du-han.
Don't act so righteous all by yourself.
I'm sad about Chunsam too.
Sigh.
Since when have you ever worried about us?
Hey.
You're talking about the past, right?
Back when you were kids.
That Pungmidang chrysanthemum bread I used to buy you every day during those hard times.
Don't you remember eating that for several meals?
I want to throw up all that chrysanthemum bread.
Hey, you really.
Sir, sir.
Sir.
Ah, why.
Why.
You just got here, why?
Give me an answer before you start drinking.
No one is coming in here.
Yes.
Go upstairs.
Here.
Here?
Hyeongdo.
Chunsam.
Wow.
Isn't something happening at Yeomcheon Bridge because of me?
What?
Why are you here?
That...
Yeomcheon Bridge is already...
a mess, and two beggars have been arrested by the police.
Who?
Parrot and Fly.
Fly too?
He's not even healthy.
They're homeless, so who knows how they'll be treated.
They must be in a terrible state by now.
Dokkae.
Yes, sir.
I smell a rotten stench coming from somewhere.
How about it?
Hey.
He's my brother.
Wait a minute.
Wow.
A runaway is living better than me.
Sitting pretty in a bathtub.
Hey.
Where are you going?
Where?
I have to go.
My kids are about to be beaten to death because of me.
They'll suffer a bit, but they won't die.
Still, I can't just leave them to get beaten.
Walking into the police station on your own two feet is insane.
They're innocent, so they'll get beaten a little and then released.
But you'll be in prison until your hair turns white, or you'll become a target.
Just hide here until tonight.
And then leave for Incheon at dawn tomorrow.
I'll find a boat that's smuggling people to Shanghai.
Oh, that's right.
Sir.
Anchovy is going to Shanghai.
I almost let him go, not knowing he was right under our noses.
Dokkae, you go to the police station now.
Yes, sir.
No.
Just keep a close watch so they don't escape.
Yes, sir.
Two.
If you like it here, come in.
Have you been keeping a good watch?
Yes, sir.
Du-han and the slippery one are gone, but that one hasn't moved an inch.
Sir.
Did Du-han go?
Yes, sir.
Where?
I'd appreciate it if you could give me a little time.
Isn't it easier to catch a frog whose limbs are limp than one that's full of energy and jumping all over the place?
And by the way.
That guy and I go way back, so I have some things to sort out with him.
It's fine to sort things out, but don't kill him.
He still has a lot to confess.
Don't you worry.
Yes, sir.
Either I die, or that guy dies, or we both die.
You guys stay here and guard this place tight.
And no matter what you hear, don't come in.
Got it?
Yes, sir.
Tell them that Kim Chunsam, the Boss of Yeomcheon Bridge, got arrested for punching a Japanese guy.
But that's not enough, so he's inciting the beggars!
I want to live my life meeting Chunsam whenever I miss him, and holding his hand whenever I want to.
That guy is going to prison.
I'll do whatever you want.
Are you from Yeomcheon Bridge?
Not Chunsam.
You have to endure it.
A Joseon beggar lives by his guts and dies by his guts
[PTT] Subtitles by knoe.ai
Precise Translation & Timing