Precise [STT] by knoe.ai
Subtitles_Translations_Timing
That's enough now.
Sir...
I'm sorry.
You foolish man...
That's not something the winner should say, you punk.
Not just anyone can raise a tiger cub like that.
Hey, let's gather the guys tonight for a drink.
We need to let people know who the new master of Jongno is, right?
Cheers!
Hey, Seung-hwan!
Sing us something exciting.
I'm honored to be here today.
I'd like to dedicate a song to Du-han, the new master of Jongno.
Man, I feel great today.
Even after all the countless days we've spent together, I've never felt as good as I do today.
There's no need to be that happy.
The best victory is one won without fighting, and we couldn't do that.
Double-Blade isn't the type to back down without a fight.
If the three of us stick together, what is there that we can't do in this land of Joseon?
Du-han has the fists.
Chunsam has the guts.
And I have this, right here.
Let's make something big happen.
What big thing?
I don't know what we'll do, but let's just say we'll be rolling in money.
Don't be so obsessed with money.
Having no money is a problem, but having too much is also a problem.
If we earn enough to cause problems, we can just give it to those who don't have any.
If you have a lot of money, you're human.
Not a human, you become a pig. A pig.
I want to be a pig.
I have no education.
No family background.
So what else is there to gain respect besides money?
Hey, hey, don't bring up money.
Do you guys know what the best thing in the world is?
The best thing in the world...
...is to love, and to be free.
Hey, you ignorant fools.
Have you ever heard of it?
Love, freedom.
Have you done it?
Chunsam must be very drunk.
Hey, hey, where are you going?
What's going to happen to Double-Blade now?
What do you mean, what?
Have you ever seen a fallen raindrop rise back up to the sky?
Anchovy!
It's been a long time since I've called you by that name.
When I saw you at the theater last time, I was so out of it I didn't even say hello.
Why are you here?
Oh, what brings you here?
Seeing you makes the fire that had set in the west rise up again, but that's all in the past.
I'm now...
...like a swallow with a broken leg.
With Kim Du-han standing tall in the middle of Gyeongseong, what power do I have to fart in front of a dung cart?
Let's get along well.
Do you know what this is?
What coin is it?
This is what Rat Droppings was holding in his hand until the very end.
Hoping to live well with his mother later.
Instead.
My wish is that no one else in this world dies like Rat Droppings, but for that to happen, a guy like you has to disappear first.
It's a shame.
Next time we meet...
...let's not part on such a sour note.
Let's have a good, hard fight until our bones are crushed.
A really hard one.
Young master.
I think there's a story about you in here.
What do these characters say?
There are too many Chinese characters.
One of the two assassins who attempted to assassinate Governor-General Endo committed suicide during interrogation and was taken to the hospital, but died.
Oh my goodness.
Fate is in the hands of heaven.
Heaven is so heartless.
Young master!
Young master, you can't go outside!
Young master, you must be strong.
Think of Lee Han-young as gone from this world.
Lee Han-young is dead.
Think only of Kim Gwa-man of Yeongcheon-gun as being alive.
Sit down.
Didn't I tell you not to beg anymore?
Have you been drinking?
How much did you make today playing the cripple?
3 won and 30 jeon.
Where is it?
2 won and 30 jeon are in the pot from when we split the money earlier.
And the rest?
The rest, you bastard!
What's the big deal if I spend it anywhere?
It's my money, after all.
I didn't hit anyone, I didn't steal anyone's money. What's wrong with begging?
Even if you can earn money, begging is the same as stealing, you bastard.
It's like stealing someone's conscience from their pocket with an invisible hand, you punk.
Are you avoiding me?
This bastard!
You're sleeping outside today.
It's still cold!
That's why you're being punished!
That woman!
Just as my sister is crazy about the Boss, are you crazy about that woman?
So you're so crazy about that woman that you don't care if my toes get frostbitten and fall off?
I'm sure it was Chuseok last year, but my heart is already...
You slept with your punishment, didn't you?
What did you do wrong?
Yesterday, I was caught by the Boss while begging in front of Pungmidang.
You idiot, the Boss told you not to beg anymore.
I did it because I need money.
Why do you need money?
The Boss takes care of our food and clothes.
Sis, you're so crazy about the Boss that you don't even see me as a flea anymore, right?
Where's a flea as big as you?
Whether you're a bedbug or a flea, you're my brother.
I'll make a mess of anyone who messes with my brother.
No matter how much you talk big, sis, it's all for nothing.
What do you know, you're just a kid.
The Boss is a man too.
When a woman wags her tail, all men fall for it.
A woman?
To other guys, I might look like a tomboy, but the Boss sees me as a woman.
He said so back then.
He asked if it was okay for a girl to steal.
Here.
Did you buy this with the money you begged for?
Yeah.
I need money sometimes too.
Oh, really.
Why are you doing something I didn't ask you to do?
Hey, I think this was made wrong.
Why are you so ugly?
Huh?
Sis, you should become a gisaeng too.
Gisaengs are all so pretty.
If you become a gisaeng, maybe the Boss will fall for you.
Ah,
I've been looking for you all morning.
Hey, did you feed the kids?
Ma'am, another bowl of soup here.
Oh, that's okay.
Ma'am.
If I eat something greasy, I'll just upset my stomach.
Hey, it feels like a hornet is buzzing around inside my head.
This is no time to be drinking.
What I hate more than rich misers are the guys who make liquor.
Try making rice with the rice they use to make liquor.
No headache, no stomach ache, a full belly, how great is that?
Just because we're poor, we don't have to hate the rich.
How great is it?
You can eat and drink.
I told you, this is not the time for drinking.
The Boss stopped the kids from begging, so now it's too hard to make a living.
You have to know how to endure hard times.
We can't survive this winter on just radish green porridge.
Hey, there were times when we couldn't even eat radish green porridge.
Think about the old days.
The old days were the old days, and now is now.
Because of those Japanese bastards making a fuss about requisitioning, the restaurant's leftover bins are half empty, and it's hard to even get a glimpse of fat from the Yukgaegwan.
Some kids are even running away.
The other day, that Beetle kid got caught stealing rice cakes from the market.
What?
Beetle?
No, he didn't steal it, he was about to...
Anyway, if we keep going like this, something bad is going to happen.
We either have to start begging again.
No begging.
This begging thing...
it's the same as stealing.
It's stealing conscience from someone else's pocket, you know.
Conscience?
Did you just say conscience?
Boss?
Yes, conscience.
Boss, what's wrong?
What?
The kids from Supyogyo and Yeongcheon all came under the Boss because they heard that the beggars of Yeomcheon Bridge share everything equally and starve together.
During the spring hardship, when even the market people had a hard time making ends meet, you even threw a rice cake party for the kids with mugwort from Inwangsan.
Do you remember that?
The Boss and I starved all day for that.
Are you talking about that kind of conscience now?
Or are you talking about the kind of conscience that gets drunk and then eats alone for a hangover cure in the morning?
Hey, Parrot.
You've changed a lot since you started seeing that woman, Boss.
I saw you in front of the photo studio.
Parrot.
What should I do?
I can only think of that woman.
I'll take some measures.
How much pain must that clover-like foot be in, all frozen?
I wish it were my foot instead.
Move!
Young master.
Our little foxtail is dying from frostbite, isn't there anything we can do?
It would be good to apply some Vaseline.
What's that?
Where do they sell it?
Try rubbing his feet.
Our young master graduated from medical school, so he's practically a doctor.
In times like this, you should listen to a nobleman.
Get out of the way!
Don't worry about whether his foot rots and falls off.
A guy like you who never washes his feet will never have that problem.
Crow gets into trouble because he washes too often.
It's not that. It's because his foot can't breathe.
Gimbap said so too.
He said it's because it's tied too tight and the blood can't circulate.
Come here for a second.
Hey, where are you going without bowing your back?
Hey!
No!
Absolutely not!
Hey, is it that hard to learn how to pickpocket?
The Boss will kill me if he finds out.
Hey, how would the Boss know?
We're just learning to pickpocket a little.
Oh, what's so great about that mangy dog-like girl?
Hey, do you still not understand how I feel?
It says so in this book too.
For a woman who can soothe a man's heart, he'll even give his soul.
Whether you give your soul or your guts, you do it alone.
Hey, are you just going to stand by and watch while Crow's toes are all frostbitten?
I won't watch, and I won't do anything.
The Boss will kill me if he finds out.
Hey, how would the Boss know?
We're just learning to pickpocket a little, without even the flea on your back knowing.
I don't want to.
Why should I, for that girl?
Are you really going to be like this?
I'm not going.
Whether you beg on your knees or prostrate yourself, I'm not going.
Hey, hey, hey.
Don't go.
There's probably no other beggar in the world as kind as you.
If you just get this one thing for me, I'll respect you more than this book.
Got it?
Respect or not, what are you talking about right now?
Next time, just put a muzzle on it.
Got it, you punk?
Alright, let's go to the pharmacy.
Let's find it.
Oh, my goodness.
She must have had a seizure.
Oh my, oh my, oh my.
Hey, move the book.
What's with this damn book?
It's better to be treated like a nobleman than to be ignored.
You have to pretend to know what's going on to get better.
Got it?
Got it.
Just a moment.
But where did you see the pharmacy?
Hello.
Hey, what does it say?
What's that?
Hey, you've been carrying books around all day and you don't even know that, you idiot?
I don't know if that's Chinese, you punk.
It seemed like Korean. How would I know?
Anyway, we'll know once we get inside the book.
Alright, I get it.
Words are words.
Korean or Chinese, they're all the same.
Hurry up.
Come out.
What are you doing?
Aren't you looking for medicine?
Got it, you punk.
You don't know that's Chinese, right?
There's a smell.
Ah, the smell is indescribable.
Not that smell, you punk.
It feels like it's right around here.
I have a feeling.
Doesn't it smell like medicine?
What smell?
You can't fool my nose.
Try farting in Mapo.
I can smell it all the way from Yeomcheon Bridge, man.
I know everything.
Follow me.
As far as they're concerned, I'm already dead.
There was a false report in the newspaper.
Since it was in the paper, there was a reason to send you.
The police must have given up on you by now.
You don't exist in this world.
Do you know that for you, I've specially brought a doctor renowned for his skills in Gyeongseong?
I've asked the doctor to treat you well more than once.
It was because I was so worried you wouldn't survive this ordeal.
I know.
I know that even if they captured your parents and tortured them in front of you, you would never open your mouth.
Unfortunately, the conscience of the Great Japanese Empire will never put a prisoner in a hospital gown on the gallows.
You need to recover quickly so you can stand in court sooner, and I can see you with a rope around your neck that much sooner.
What a stubborn woman.
Are you giving up on your sainthood?
I don't have time for that.
I have to find Lee Han-young.
Lee Han-young!
That's the cop who raided our shack looking for your Young Master.
That sign clearly said Lee Han-young.
So what?
He's not our Young Master.
Gimbap?
Yeah.
That woman who's inside isn't dead.
Manager, someone is waiting for you over there.
Has Manager Abe arrived?
It's an honor to meet you like this.
I've always wanted to meet someone like you, sir.
Who are you?
I'm just a guy who gathers the homeless in the back alleys of Bokrae-dong in Namdaemun and tries to make a living.
I came here to pay my respects to the great police chief of the Japanese Empire who is working hard for the peace of Gyeongseong.
Did you come all this way just for that?
That's not all.
I heard that the police station is short on people lately.
I was thinking of using a guy named Anchovy from Yeomcheon Bridge, but it was a total failure.
Even if I were to be reborn, I wouldn't be any different from that guy.
Manager, you've completely misjudged the man.
That kid is a bull in a china shop. He'd die from my tail whip. How can you say he's no different from me?
Min-jae... is Min-jae in that hospital?
It's true.
The newspaper said she was dead.
We saw it.
Hey, we saw it, right?
Right?
Huh?
Uh, uh, uh.
That policeman who my mom was with.
He said that the woman wouldn't talk even if she died, so they had to catch the young master quickly.
How's the security at the hospital room?
How many are guarding it?
In front of the main entrance of the hospital.
There are two guards.
And there's another one guarding right in front of the hospital room.
They're all carrying guns, so we can't even dream of getting close.
Hey, the young master will take care of the dreaming part. What do you know to be talking like that?
He's not in critical condition, is he?
I don't know if he's in critical condition.
The nurse and the doctor were going in and out a lot.
Where's the Boss now?
He's probably at the King Star.
With Du-han.
No, where are you going?
I have to meet him.
Right now.
But they even know your name, Young Master. Are you going out into the city?
You have a horse that understands human speech and knows everything. Where are you going?
I'm not going!
Where are you going in the evening?
I'm starving.
There's no other kind beggar like you in the world.
If you just go to the Boss once this time, I'll respect you more than I respect this book.
No, I said I'm not going.
Are you really going to do this again?
I'm not going!
It's better to differentiate based on income.
The individual rooms or side rooms behind this pavilion don't bring in much money, so you can charge 2 won.
But in the case of the shrine or the gilt house on the other side of the lamp, they look shabby on the outside.
But it can be fun.
You can charge 3 won.
Got it.
Hey, and by the way.
From now on...
If there's a gathering of influential people in the city, you go there yourself and make a good impression.
Those Japanese bastards need to know who they're doing business with, right?
That's right.
And as I always say, take care of our kids' jobs. A theater guard is fine, a hotel errand boy is fine. Our kids can do anything.
And one more thing, you.
You have to act like a real boss.
What are you wearing?
First of all, if you're a boss, you have to slick your hair back.
Slick it back, I said.
Make your forehead shiny.
And then Double-Blade, that little dwarf.
Why are you wearing stripes?
Stripes suit you.
Try wearing a suit with pinstripes.
And like Double-Blade, don't interfere when you shouldn't, and interfere when you should.
You haven't even been buried yet.
Look at Double-Blade's face.
After being beaten by his underling, he has to go to Manchuria.
Huh?
Manchuria is a bit...
Manchuria.
Hey, that bastard.
He likes face and all that, but he hates bad smells.
But why go there, man?
It's our land too.
No.
That's not it.
Everyone said you went to Manchuria, sir.
I've lived in Jongno for 30 years, and I'll live here for that much longer.
Just because I took off my jacket for Du-han, has the sentiment in this neighborhood become so harsh that I can't live here anymore?
Is that right, Du-han?
No, sir.
Before the blood from the double-edged sword has even dried, has the spirit of the fists in this neighborhood become so dirty that you would stab me in the back, Du-han?
Yes, I know.
I'm a stray dog that has left its home now.
I know it's pathetic to be sniffing around the gate again.
But, my 30 years in Jongno, my 30 years with these fists, are so sad.
The road to Manchuria is too far, Du-han.
Why go all the way to Manchuria to eat Chinese pancakes?
They're more delicious here.
Grasshopper, get your Double-Blade brother the biggest glass of gwiraso hyangju.
Yes, yes.
If a ladder knows how to go up, it should also know how to come down.
I only learned how to win fights, not how to lose.
Hey, if you don't know, I'll show you the way.
Just because the old Boss came under me, doesn't mean I'll ignore him.
Right?
Boss!
There's a problem.
I think you need to go to Yeomcheon Bridge.
Why?
Well, Gimbap told me to get you, sir.
Who's Gimbap?
Got a cigarette?
Money is good, but a person's life is more important.
That's exactly what I wanted to say.
If you lend me a little bit of your strength, we can save the life of a great comrade who is fighting for independence.
If we get caught, what are you going to do about the lives of the beggars?
I know the structure of the hospital well because I've been in and out of it a lot for the past two years in Gyeongseong.
If we plan it well, there will be no great danger.
How much will you give us?
We won't do it for any amount.
Didn't I tell you?
We can't last long on just trash.
But if we get caught, we'll rot in jail for the rest of our lives.
No.
If we just do as the young master says, we can get him out without any trouble.
What do you mean, no trouble, man?
We're trying to get a person out of a place guarded by three patrolmen with guns.
It's one or the other.
Either we listen to him, or we go back to begging, or we all starve to death.
I'd rather starve to death.
If everything had gone according to plan, I would be on a cruise ship on the Huangpu River in Shanghai right now.
With my wife.
Are you married?
No, I couldn't.
The person who was supposed to be my wife is now lying in a hospital bed in Gyeongseong.
The plan was to assassinate Governor-General Endo and get married in Shanghai.
She's the woman who taught me about freedom and love.
Oh, so that note...
Yes.
You of all people should know how precious love is to a man.
What's love...
It's more precious than anything in the world.
More than honor, wealth, and money.
How much can you get?
I can get 300 won.
That's enough to buy thirty bags of rice...
It's not because of the woman.
I just want to put some warm rice in our kids' stomachs for a change.
Hama!
Don't forget Ms. Park Hyeon-sim.
Yes, I understand.
I came to see Ms. Park Hyeon-sim.
I've read Mr. Park Gye-ju's book three and a half times.
My name is Choi Hong-pal.
No one knows me as Choi Hong-pal.
They call me Hama.
My real name is Man-suk...
The director sent this again.
The Director of Finance at the Government-General is no ordinary person. What are you relying on to be so arrogant?
I'm not relying on anything.
What kind of gift is it this time?
Don't touch it.
Can't I just take a little peek and then glue it back with rice paste?
No.
I don't know why men are so stupid.
They don't even think of giving a rice cake to someone who's dying for one, and they keep sending them to someone who runs away scared at the sight of one.
Then you take it.
You can meet Director Ikeda, too.
No thanks.
Why would I meet a man who's desperately clinging to you?
Where did you get that?
It was all dried up and shriveled in the corner of your room.
It was going to be eaten anyway, so what does it matter who eats it?
It wasn't for eating.
Then what?
You were going to keep it, looking at it over and over until it got all shriveled up, weren't you?
What am I going to do? I'm so sorry.
I'll buy you another tangerine.
Even if you buy me a gold one or a silver one, or a whole box, it won't be the same.
Did that Kim Chunsam person give you that?
You really don't know how to judge men.
The real man among men is Kim Du-han.
His shoulders are as broad as a school playground, and his fists are as hard as iron.
Don't you think the flower of youth will bloom brilliantly if you get to be held in the arms of such a wonderful man just once?
Um...
Please!
No, Park-no!
Um, that's not...
Who are you?
I'm not a suspicious or bad person.
I'm a respectable person who respects books, so please don't worry.
And this book is a book that I respect very much.
I've read it three and a half times, staying up all night in感動.
And this book is...
Are you... from Yeomcheon Bridge?
Yes, that's right.
But I didn't come here representing Yeomcheon Bridge.
What's the matter?
I came to see Ms. Park Hyeon-sim.
Park Hyeon-sim?
Who's Park Hyeon-sim?
There's no gisaeng like that here.
Ms. Park isn't here right now.
She'll be here tomorrow, but what's the matter?
The Boss takes the disguised me to the warehouse and immediately fixes the cart and waits outside the emergency room entrance.
Meanwhile, Parrot, disguised as a doctor, says Min-jae is in critical condition, takes him out of the hospital room, and brings him to the emergency room.
Wait...
How do you make a healthy person into a corpse?
You kill him.
Hey, be quiet.
Okay.
Gimbap, continue.
Once in the emergency room, there's a side door leading outside.
We take him out through there and load him onto the waiting cart.
If you just cover him with a sheet, he becomes a corpse.
What do you say if they ask why you're taking the corpse back?
You can say he was rejected because he was too decomposed.
Wait, how do you make a fresh corpse decompose?
You can just leave it in a warm furnace to rot.
Sit down.
Hey, that's enough.
I told you to be quiet.
Sit down.
Just be quiet.
What about the patrolmen?
They probably won't come inside the emergency room.
Even if they try to, we have to stop them.
How do you get out?
Let's walk out of the warehouse on our bare feet.
Wait, how does a corpse walk out?
He's supposed to be a corpse.
See, this is a problem.
This is completely insane.
No, if I pretend to be sick...
Doesn't this make no sense?
Hey, that's enough.
That's enough.
Be quiet.
Gimbap knows the hospital well, so he can get out on his own.
Alright, everyone understands?
Alright, listen up again.
Parrot will change clothes in this changing room, go to this hospital room, get Min-jae, and come to the emergency room.
Out the side door of the emergency room.
Alright, got it?
Hey, that's enough.
That's enough.
Fly, you take Gimbap to the dye factory and paint him blue.
Got it?
And Parrot, you take Raccoon and fix the broken cart.
Oh, and Fly, you stay in the shack with Crow.
Hey, Boss, why are you leaving me out?
It would be much safer to leave out Left Foot.
Hey, hey, shut up.
Shut up.
Someone has to stay behind and look after the little ones.
But, Boss, I'm, I'm much better than him...
Hey, why are you ignoring me?
Hey, you punk.
Give me my clothes.
Hey, wait a minute.
Did you meet them?
Yes.
And the money?
The chopsticks?
Yes.
Good work.
The chopsticks, right?
Give me my clothes.
Hey, Hama.
Let me see it.
I counted it, there's a lot.
Yeah, let me see.
It's over 300 won.
Young master, is this ours now?
I couldn't meet him.
He was out somewhere.
Give me my clothes.
Fly and I are dead.
I couldn't get it.
Boss, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to deceive you, Boss.
I just wanted to help the young master in any way I could.
I couldn't get it today, but...
I'll definitely be able to get it next time.
Hey, Hama.
Go get the cart wheels.
I'm so heavy.
Oh, right.
Hama.
Let me see the money.
I've never spent 300 won in my life.
Go and get ready.
Get ready.
Hey, Hama.
Keep the money safe.
Got it?
Yes!
Got it.
You bastard.
You're joking around when you're supposed to be getting ready.
Hey!
Hey, Hama.
Hurry up.
Be careful.
This is heavy.
Okay.
Grab it.
It's not heavy.
Hey, hold on to that fly.
Hey, it's not heavy.
Why are you taking that?
To take a bath.
Hey.
Hey, what about this?
Hey,
Hey, hey.
Hama, stop hitting.
Hurry.
Hey, Barefoot.
Catch.
Barefoot.
Just a moment.
Hey, where did Raccoon go?
He's in the back.
Raccoon, hurry up and come out.
Hey, that's enough.
Tell him to stay behind and guard the shack.
Hey, let's go.
Let's go.
Boss, can't I go instead of Raccoon?
That's enough.
Stay here with your sister.
Is that bitch Haewol really all that?
How pretty is she?
Now that I think about it, she's just so-so.
Don't lie and tell me the truth. How pretty is she?
Sis.
No matter how good a rubber shoe is, it looks like trash next to a leather shoe.
Sis, when we're together, we're like rubber shoes, but
honestly, next to a gisaeng, we're not even straw sandals.
What should I say if they ask how he died?
Say he starved to death.
Say he froze to death.
It's better to say he died from an illness.
You have no right to judge me.
Nurse, please call a doctor from the emergency room quickly.
What doctor?
Where?
Go to the emergency room and get him quickly.
What?
Did you say they use students to practice cutting people open in this hospital?
I came because they said they'd give me some money for a corpse, but he has a disease.
I'm going to get a disease.
Go in.
Sir, where is the emergency room?
I collapsed after vomiting and having diarrhea all day...
It's over there to the left.
Thank you, sir.
Well
I don't know.
Is it a sport?
Get the doctor ready.
Yes, I understand.
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Are you coming from Ogin-dong?
Are you coming from the homeless shelter in Ogin-dong?
Pardon?
Yes.
Ah, so you're just coming home now?
Follow me!
Hey, what are you doing?
Aren't you going to follow me?
Hey, corpse!
Be quiet!
Ah, really...
Come this way, this way.
Leave it over there and go.
Oh, lay the corpse down properly.
What time does this gentleman plan to start?
Sigh...
Huh?
Hey, hyung, this is a woman's.
She has breasts.
I see.
Young master, what should we do?
Let's just wait a bit.
What if they think she's really dead and cut her open...
Don't worry.
She's not a real corpse.
We're in big trouble.
What should we do?
I don't know.
Don't ask me.
Button up, you bastard.
Hey, Boss...
If he doesn't come out, should I go in and lie to him?
Stop pushing me.
That's not it.
A woman's heart is weaker than a foxtail, so can't you say something warm to Crow once in a while?
That poor thing only has eyes for you, Boss. I'm worried she'll go crazy if she finds out you're interested in someone else.
What are you doing?
Let's go.
Hey, where are you?
Is it sushi today?
The order was sitting right here.
Oh, you stupid bastard.
You don't know where it is?
Why don't you know?
It's one of two.
So which of the two is it?
I miss the future or a bear's paw.
I'm not a bear's paw.
I'm Barefoot.
Hey, I got it.
Stop nagging and just tell me.
Is it here or there?
Where is it?
Uh.
It's here.
Where is it?
There's no one here.
It's the next room.
See, I was right.
I told you it was this room.
Here, cover her up quickly.
Okay.
Be quiet.
We came to rescue you.
Gimbap.
You know Gimbap, right?
Be quiet.
Boss, it's done.
We found the right one.
We need to get out of here.
What about the young master?
Where did Gimbap go?
Get him quickly.
We're all going to die.
What about the young master?
I don't know.
Take him and wait.
Got it?
Got it, Boss.
Be quiet.
Can't you move a little faster?
Come on, hurry.
Sir, good work.
Getting antibiotics wasn't easy.
We're lucky to have this much.
By the way, you're doing an autopsy with Dr. Park, right?
You go ahead.
We'll take care of this patient.
Good luck.
Sir, isn't it too late?
We can do it tomorrow.
This guy is already talking about dying.
Hurry up and prepare.
I didn't get a wink of sleep last night.
This is going to rot quickly.
I'm going to the director's office, so get him ready for the autopsy and wait.
Got it?
Yes.
Be prepared to die tonight.
Sir, what happened?
What happened?
Sir, please save me.
Be quiet.
I'm risking my life to save you.
Hey, man, man.
Sir!
Min-jae.
Let's go.
Did something go wrong?
This isn't the woman.
What?
No, I told you it was that ugly guy.
It can't be.
I saw him sitting there.
Tell me exactly.
I think the rooms were switched.
What do we do?
We have to go back in and get him.
We can't just search all the rooms.
You said there was a side door behind the emergency room, right?
No, there are always people there.
Hey, there's an order in front of the emergency room.
Hey, what?
Hey, hey, hey.
Be quiet.
Was there an order in front of the emergency room?
Yes, definitely.
We couldn't have come out.
He must have gone back to his room.
Fine.
I'm going back in.
Listen up.
Gimbap and Parrot, follow me.
Gimbap and I will go and get that woman from her room.
Parrot, you take care of the emergency room.
Pardon?
To distract the patrolmen, we have to go through the emergency room. You do something with the nurses in the meantime.
No, what am I supposed to do?
Seduce them or kill them, you figure it out.
If we get caught, we're all dead.
That's why I didn't want to come in the first place.
Who was the one who came because he wanted 300 won?
Shut up and distract them well.
Distract them even if you have to throw a fit.
Got it?
If we get caught, we're all dead.
Barefoot.
Take off those clothes.
Boss, what about this woman?
Hold her.
In the rainy street...
Do we need to move her back to the emergency room?
Pardon?
My sister is gone.
What, a gisaeng house?
Why a gisaeng house?
Chunsam, he's not a gangster.
I'll go on my own, so don't follow me...
That guy from Yeomcheon Bridge...
What kind of teacher is that?
He's the kind of guy who hates it when someone gets something without working for it.
Precise [STT] by knoe.ai
Subtitles_Translations_Timing